我不想成为环境的产物
I don't wanna be a product of my environment.
相反，我希望环境为我所左右
I want my environment to be a product of me.
很多年前，我们拥有一座教堂
Years ago, we had the Church.
那仅是表示我们彼此团结的一种方式
That was only a way of saying we had each other.
但是现在，我不清楚 它很可笑
But now, I don't know. It's a funny thing.
它向你心中灌输仇恨
It put hate in your heart.
哥伦布骑士是真正的意大利强硬派
The Knights of Columbus were real head-breakers.
True guineas.
他们在城市中开辟了自己的地盘
They took over their piece of the city.
20年前，爱尔兰人连工作都找不到
Twenty years after an Irishman couldn't get a fucking job...
现在我们终于迎来了安稳的生活
...we had the presidency. May he rest in peace.
这就是那些黑鬼们没有意识到的
That's what the niggers don't realize.
如果说我对那些黑鬼有什么成见的话 那就是这个了
If I got one thing against the black chappies, it's this:
没人会施舍给你
No one gives it to you.
你得自己争取
You have to take it.
文，别再让我亲自上门来要钱了
Vin, don't make me have to come down here again for this.
不会再有下次的，C先生
Wort happen again, Mr. C.
卡门已经出落成小美人了
Carmers developing into a fine young lady.
你应该骄傲
You should be proud.
开始来例假了没，卡门？
You get your period yet, Carmen?
你是强尼・苏利文的儿子？
You Johnny Sullivars kid?
- 你和你奶奶一起住？ - 对
- You live with your grandmother? - Yeah.
文，给他拿些面包和牛奶
Vin, get him a couple loaves of bread, couple half-gallons of milk.
你喜欢腊肠和奶酪吗？ 再来点冷盘
Do you like bologna and cheese? Give him some cold cuts.
还有蛋黄酱 喜欢看漫画书吗？
Throw some mayo in. You like comic books?
你学习好吗？
You do good in school?
- 还行 - 不错，我以前也是
- Yeah. - That's good. I did too.
他们说这点和我本人自相矛盾
They call that a paradox.
不用找了，给你自己买点化妆品吧
Just keep it. Buy yourself some makeup.
要是想赚零花钱的话 就到L街来找我
You ever wanna earn a little extra money, you come by L Street.
你知道在我在L街的哪里？
You know where I am on L Street?
很好
Good.
- 乖孩子 - 谢谢
- Good boy. - Thanks.
主啊，您忠实的仆人
To you, O Lord, we commend the soul of Alphonsus, your servant.
在这个世界已经不复存在
In the sight of this world, he is now dead.
请饶恕他因人性弱点而犯下的罪过
Forgive whatever sins he committed through human weakness.
- 阿门 - 教会要你听话
- Amen. - The Church wants you in your place.
说站就站，说跪就跪
Kneel, stand, kneel, stand.
如果你想干这种事 我不知道还为你做什么
If you go for that sort of thing, I don't know what to do for you.
路都是自己走出来的
A man makes his own way.
没人会施舍给你
No one gives it to you.
你得自己争取
You have to take it.
- - 这是詹姆士・乔伊斯（著名作家）说的 - 聪明，科林
- James Joyce. - Smart, Colin.
如果普罗维登斯的意大利佬
Guineas from the North End, down Providence...
跑到这来对我指手画脚
...tried to tell me what to do.
那他们就有麻烦了
And something maybe happened to them.
也许，就像那样
Maybe like that:
天，她倒下的姿势可真可笑
Jeez. She fell funny.
弗兰克，你应该去看看心理医生了
Francis, you really should see somebody.
一旦你树立了目标，你就能实现
When you decide to be something, you can be it.
这个教会没有教你的
That's what they don't tell you in the Church.
我像你这么大的时候，他们说 我们可能成为警察或者罪犯
When I was your age, they would say we could become cops or criminals.
今天，我要对你这么说
Today what I'm saying to you is this:
当你面对着一把上了膛的枪时
When you're facing a loaded gun...
这两者又有什么区别呢？
...what's the difference?
乖孩子
That's my boy.
弹道学是研究发射体
Terminal ballistics is the study of a projectile...
以及击中目标后对其所造成破坏的学科
...as it hits a target and the destruction that it causes.
以你们的佩枪为例，9毫米空尖弹
Take, for instance, what you carry, 9 mm hollow-point.
当空尖弹击中头骨时 它会爆炸
When the hollow-point hits the skull, what happens is it mushrooms.
爆炸时弹片剥落 你可能会遇到6个，8个或10个
When it mushrooms it peels back. So you may have six, eight...
像刀片一样的子弹残粒
...ten little particles of the bullet that are like razor blades...
是的，长官
Sir, yes, sir!
撕裂他们的内脏 肝，肺，心脏
- Tearing their internal organs, their liver, their lungs, their heart...
内部组织，血液，大脑 …这就叫气体反冲
...bringing tissue, bone, blood, brain matter, and that's called a blowback.
去你妈的，一帮娘们
Fuck you. Fucking queers.
消防员第一次面对大火或女人时很逊
Firemen getting pussy for the first time in the history of fire or pussy.
嗨，快回去救困在树上的猫吧 你们这些混蛋同性恋
Hey, go save a kitten in a tree, you fucking homos.
铅笔准备好
Pencils.
开始
Begin.
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
别想了
Forget it.
老爸是看大门的 儿子就只有当警察的命
Your father was a janitor, his sors only a cop.
那帮他妈的消防员都是同性恋
Those fucking firefighters are a bunch of homos.
确实
They are.
她对我说，你从来没完成过任何事 等你完成了警校的课程
So she tells me, "You never finish anything. You finish the police course...
我就再和你好，宝贝 等毕业了，她就又给我爽了
...you get taken care of again, baby." So after graduation, I get a blowjob again.
不错啊了，你妈一定是个了不起的女人
That's great. Your mother must be a wonderful woman.
去你的
Fuck yourself.
这么说吧，你是波士顿黑人
Put it this way. You're a black guy in Boston.
不需要我动手就有人来整你了
You don't need any help from me to be completely fucked.
麻萨诸塞州警察拥有悠久的良好声誉
The Massachusetts State Police has a long tradition of excellence.
今天你们在此毕业
Your graduation today solidifies your acceptance...
即将成为我们国家优秀的警务人员
...into one of the finest law enforcement agencies in our nation.
做为马萨诸塞州警务主管
As the governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, I am confident...
我坚信，你们每一个人 都将出色，荣耀，诚实地效忠国家
...each and every one of you will serve with distinction, honor and integrity.
祝贺大家
Congratulations to all our new troopers.
谢谢，你们可以解散了
Thank you. You are dismissed.
苏利文，你刚毕业就是便衣 祝贺你
Sullivan, assigned to plainclothes right out of the gate, congratulations.
- 我们要去喝一杯，一起来吗？ - 不了，我一会去找你们
- We're going for a beer. You wanna come? - No, I'll catch up with you guys.
再也不用上学了
School's out.
弗兰克，谢谢
Thank you, Frank.
你应得的
You earned it.
不用再念书了
No more pencils, no more books.
好
All right.
这里不是普通的警队
This is not the regular police...
- …是州立警队 - 开枪！
...this is the state police. - And fire!
你们的训练会证明有什么不同
Your training will illustrate the difference.
州警察，有搜查证！ 州警察，开门！
State police, search warrant! State police, open the door!
有什么不同？
What's the difference?
- 上！上！ - 是的，长官！
- Go, go, go! - Sir, yes, sir!
- 明白！ - 是的，长官！
- Is that understood? - Sir, yes, sir!
给我趴下！快趴下！
Move it, get the fuck down right now. Get down, right now.
恭喜你通过了警探考核
Congratulations on passing the detective's exam, and welcome...
…欢迎加入我们特别调查组 - 看你他妈的那德行
...to the Special Investigation Unit. - Whoop-de-fucking-do.
我们以后不会一起工作，直接地说
We won't be working together, that is, directly.
你会跟艾勒文队长 但我希望能看下你们每个人
You'll be working for Captain Ellerby, but I like to see everybody.
只要你努力，就会很快升职的
You're a worker. You rise fast.
就像十二岁孩子的阳具
Like a 12-year-old's dick.
- 谢谢警官 - 不客气
- Thank you, sergeant. - My pleasure.
- 谢谢长官 - 祝你好运
- Thank you, sir. - Good luck.
- 祝贺你 - 谢谢，亲爱的
- Congratulations. - Thanks, hon.
你现在可以进去了
You can go in there now.
请坐
You can sit.
嗯…
So...
你知道我们是做什么的吗？ 我这个部门？
Do you know what we do here? My section?
- 是的，长官，我知道… - 你根本什么都不知道…
- Yes, sir, I have an idea... - Let's say you have no idea...
懂吗？什么都不知道
...and leave it at that, okay?
不知道
No idea. Zip. None.
如果你知道我们是做什么的 那就说明我们做的不好，是不是？
If you had an idea what we do, we would not be good at what we do, would we?
那我们就成狗屁了
We would be cunts.
你是不是叫我们狗屁？
Are you calling us cunts?
迪克曼警官有他自己的处事风格
Staff Sergeant Dignam has a style of his own.
恐怕我们都得去适应
I'm afraid we all have to get used to it.
你家和南波士顿的黑帮有关系，对吧？ 通过你父亲？
So you have family connections down in Southie, right? Through your father?
和我们说说你叔叔杰西吧
Why don't you tell us about your Uncle Jackie?
他是乔治・马沙的手下
He was a carpet layer for Jordan Marsh.
他只不过是个三流管帐而已 在萨默维尔管个小酒吧
Uncle Jackie was a small-time bookie who tended bar at the Vets in Somerville.
他95年被人干掉了 我们在机场里发现了他的尸体
He got popped by Nicastro in '95. We found his body out by the airport.
没错
That's right.
- 我还记得他的葬礼 - 不错
- I remember his funeral. - Oh, good.
棺材是盖着的吧？
Closed casket?
没错
That's right.
告诉大家在你因为用椅子 痛打一个体育老师
So tell anybody up at Deerfield...
被开除之前你在预科学校的事
Before you got kicked out for whaling on a gym teacher with a chair.
你叔叔就像那样挂掉的？
- You had an uncle met his demise like that?
我有个问题
I got a question.
你这人到底多衰？
How fucked up are you?
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, Darlene.
有什么好消息吗，参谋警官？ 用不了多久你就能当上警官了
What you got, staff sergeant? In no time you made sergeant.
- 特别调查组，很牛吧 - 太好了
- SIU. What a country. - Perfect.
我不介意一个人独闯
Hey, I don't mind going it alone.
如果你偶尔也独闯的话 可能有机会出头
You know, if you went alone once in a while you might get somewhere.
我们是警察，这不是出人投地
We're cops, all right? This isn't somewhere.
我知道你很努力，也许我能帮你一把
All right, lookit, I know you're a worker. Maybe I can do something for you.
你家里有没有西装？
You got any suits, or do you like...
还是你就喜欢 穿得跟要进攻波兰一样
...coming to work dressed like you're gonna invade Poland?
小子，你家族可不简单啊 你另一个叔叔
You got quite the family tree. That maggot uncle of yours...
汤米・科斯提根也是个傻子，他因为…
...Tommy Costigan, is another goof. He gets busted selling guns...
贩卖枪支给联邦警察而被捕 这只是他众多傻事中的一件
...to federal officers, among many, many, many other departures...
这些和我有什么关系？
...from our normative behavior. - And what's this got to do with me?
为什么你要假装做警察？
Why are you pretending to be a cop?
这是个新部门，你们也都是新人
This unit is new, and you are the newest members of it.
你们都是我们精选出来的人才
You have been selected for it on the basis of intelligence and aptitude.
这是精英部门
This is an elite unit.
我们的工作就是粉碎 或者说小规模地折腾一下
Our job is to smash or marginally disrupt...
城里有组织的犯罪团体
...organized crime in this city...
我们与联邦调查局的紧密合作
...by enanced cooperation with the FBI...
弗兰克・拉齐奥探员是他们的代表
...represented here today by Agent Frank Lazio.
我们会做到的
And we will do it.
城里有组织的犯罪团体 你们知道我们指的是谁
And by organized crime in this city, you know who we mean.
杰西・科斯提根，这张是他的旧照
That's Jackie Costigan. That's an old picture.
杰西已经死了
Jackie met his demise.
最后的遗照
Last known photograph.
卡斯特罗手下有3员大将
Costello uses three key guys.
菲兹，疯子移民 和他妈一起住在德拉大街上
That's Fitzy. Off-the-boat psycho, lives in Brockton with his mother.
她也有点疯
She's straight out of Going My Way.
德拉亨特，外号肌肉男
Delahunt, muscle.
法国佬，他的头号大将 当然，还有你们都知道的我们的头号明星
French, the number one. But of course, the rock star, you-know-who.
我们已经作了一份简报 读一读，有任何提议就告诉我
We've done a briefing book, so read up. I want all ideas...
这样我才可以拿去自己邀功
...so I can pass them off as my own.
只要你们好好干，就会很快升迁的
Work hard, you'll rise fast. You're in the best possible position...
现在就是你们最好的机会 开始干活吧
...in the department. Let's go to work.
你老爸在南波士顿卖苦力
Your old man was a fucking hump from Southie.
机场的行李搬运工，是吧？
Baggage handler at the airport, right?
除了你老爸，你家其他人都是罪犯吧？
Family's all criminals except for the old man, huh?
还有个牧师呢 看上去你无所不知呢
And one priest, since you seem to know everything.
我还听说他和一个12岁的小男孩结了婚 一起住在泰国的海滨呢
Last I heard he was married to a 12-year-old boy, living on a beach in Thailand.
你们一家像虱子一样扎根在南波士顿
Fucking family's dug into the Southie projects like ticks.
最多住着三层房子 而你…
Three-decker men at best. You, however, grew up...
却在北岸长大，对吗？ 真他妈的
...on the North Shore, huh? Well, la-di-fucking-da.
你是个有双重性格的小子吧？
You were kind of a double kid, I bet, right?
和你老爸在一起时一个样 和你老妈在一起时另一个样
One kid with your old man, one kid with your mother.
你平时以中产阶级自居，到了周末
You're upper-middle class during the weeks, then you're hanging...
而到周末就跑到南岸你老爸那去
...in the Southie projects with your daddy, the fucking donkey...
我说得没错吧
...on the weekends. I got that right?
你有不同的口音吧？
Yup. You have different accents?
你有，是不是？你他妈这个小骗子
You did, didn't you, you little fucking snake?
- 你就是两面派 - 你是精神分析师？
- You were like different people. - You a psychiatrist?
如果我是的话 我会问你为何甘愿做州警领这区区3万元
If I was, I'd ask you why you're a statie making 30 grand a year.
就算我他妈是弗洛伊德的话 我也不知道答案
And I think if I was Sigmund fucking Freud I wouldn't get an answer.
你告诉我，像你这样的混蛋 在州警队里干什么？
Tell me, what's a lace-curtain motherfucker like you doing in the staties?
美国家庭总是起起落落，对吗？
Well, families are always rising or falling in America, am I right?
这话是谁说的？ - 霍桑
- Who said that? - Hawthorne.
你他妈怎么了 就不会说点莎士比亚的吗？
What's the matter, smart-ass, you don't know any fucking Shakespeare?
我们有个问题
We have a question.
你是真想做警察 还是想看上去像个警察
Do you wanna be a cop, or do you wanna appear to be a cop?
希望你能诚实回答
It's an honest question.
很多人只是觉得当警察很酷 佩枪，警徽，像电视上一样
Lot of guys want to appear to be cops. Gun, badge, pretend they're on TV.
很多人只是想找个借口教训黑鬼
A lot of them just wanna slam a nigger through a window...
我听够了你那些个人工作的狗屁话
I'm set without your own personal job application, sergeant.
- 你说什么？小子 - 你们到底想让我干什么？
- What did you say? - Sir, what do you want from me?
嗨，混蛋，他帮不了你
Hey, he can't help you.
我知道你是什么人 我知道你是什么人…
I know what you are. I know what you are...
我也知道你不是什么人
...and I know what you're not.
我是最了解你的人 而且我要告诉你，混蛋
I'm the best friend you have and I'm gonna help you understand something.
你不是他妈的警察！
You're no fucking cop.
他说的没错 我们这里调查的是外面那些人
He's right. We deal in deception here.
而不是自己人的欺诈行为
What we do not deal with is self-deception.
从现在起5年内，你可以成为任何人
Five years from now you could be anything else in the world.
但你不会成为马萨诸塞州警员
But you will not be a Massachusetts state trooper.
- 你确定吗？ - 我确定
- Are you sure of that? - I'm sure of that.
我他妈的保证
Guaran-fucking-teed.
你大学入学考试得了1400分 这分够当宇航员的了，还当什么警察
You had 1400 on your SATs, kid. You're an astronaut, not a statie.
你没有什么家人了
You don't have much family.
- 我没有任何家人
I don't have any family.
听斯蒂芬尼说你要当上警察了 这是怎么回事？
What's this I hear from Stephanie about you becoming a policeman?
你说的是那个唯一来参加 我爸葬礼的？
Stephanie, who was the only one who came to my father's funeral?
- 那个斯蒂芬尼？ - 对，那个斯蒂芬尼
- That Stephanie? - Yeah, that Stephanie.
- 没什么好说的，爱德华叔叔 - 你想证明什么给你家人看吗？
- Nothing much to it, Uncle Edward. - Trying to prove something to the family?
你说家人，你指的是谁？你吗？
When you say "the family," who do you mean exactly? You?
你总是要置疑一切，是吗？
You always have to question everything, don't you?
也许时不时地问自己一些问题对你有好处
Maybe it would've done you some good to have some questions from time to time.
我是混蛋吗？我的孩子很糟糕吗？
"Am I an asshole? Are my kids a mess?
我老婆是不是个贪财的婊子？ 这些都是问题，对吧？
Is my wife a money-grubbing whore?" I mean, those are questions, right?
我是否好好对待过我垂死的姐姐？ 还是我现在只是假装这样？
"Have I ever been good to my dying sister, or am I just now pretending to be?"
你需要钱准备葬礼吗？
Do you need some money for the funeral?
我妈妈去世后，我们就再无瓜葛
When my mother dies, we don't have any more connection.
这房子很漂亮，天花板很高 木地板，浴室也很大
It's lovely. You get the high ceilings, the parquet floors. Bathroom is massive.
冰箱上有警报器
The fridge has got an alarm in it in case you have...
以防你吃饭噎着 开玩笑的…其实不是很好笑
...eating issues, which is a joke. Not a very funny one.
这里看市政厅，灯塔山也是一目了然
Well, there's a great view of the State House. Beacon Hill, you can see it.
你要是搬进来的话 马上就能成马萨诸塞州的上流阶级
I mean, you move in, you're upper-class by about Tuesday.
- 那么你是警察了 - 州警探
- So you're a cop. - A state-police detective.
州警探
A state-police detective.
你是个结了婚的州警探吗？
And are you a married state-police detective?
不是
No.
这房子…一个人住有点大了
Because this is kind of a... Sort of a big place and...
我有合租人
I have a co-signer.
那不错，你有客人会来，很好
Oh, cool. Yeah, you intend to have a houseguest. That's cool. Good.
- 嗯… - 把合同给我
- Yeah, it's got... - Just give me the papers.
行
Sure.
主啊，请赋予她永恒的安宁 让光明永照其身
Eternal rest grant unto her, O Lord, and let perpetual light shine upon her.
- 阿门 - 愿她安息，阿门
- Amen. - May she rest in peace. Amen.
愿她的灵魂籍主的恩慈
May her soul and the souls of all the faithful departed...
永远安息
...through the mercy of God rest in peace.
阿门
Amen.
天堂收留虔诚的逝者，弗兰克・卡斯特罗
要我干什么？
So what do I do?
这个行动有资金支持 我们不会像普通警察那样付你工资
There's money behind this operation. You won't be paid as a regular cop...
这里有奖金
...but there's a bonus involved.
免税的
Tax-free.
我们无法隐瞒你曾是警校学员的事实 你要去犯罪
We can't conceal that you were a trainee. You'll be convicted of a crime.
我们想有恶性伤人案底的警察 可能会比较可信
We're thinking a guilty plea to assault and battery would make sense.
正好符合你的本性
Given your nature.
你要在牢里呆段时间 好叫别人相信这一切都不是圈套
You'll do enough jail time to convince anyone this is no setup.
之后你会被假释 看法庭指定的心理医生
You'll be on probation, see a court-ordered shrink...
做整套戏
...the whole nine yards.
你想为国家效力，这是个好机会
You wanna serve the Commonwealth, this is your chance.
我们需要你，老兄
We need you, pal.
你已经假装是南波士顿的卡斯提根了
You've already pretended to be a Costigan from South Boston.
- 只有每个周末才是，警官 - 好极了
- Every weekend, sergeant. - Perfect.
再做一次
Do it again.
为了我
For me.
片名：《无间行者》 又译：《无间道风云》
- 你是比尔・卡斯提根？ - 对，怎么了？
- Hey, you Billy Costigan? - Yeah, who wants to know?
没什么，我认识一个叫肖恩・科斯提根的 他住在L街
Well, nothing. I know a Sean Costigan down on L Street.
- 那是我表兄 - 我认识他，那家伙很不识相
- Yeah, that's my cousin. - Connected. Not too bright.
- 我知道 - 我并不想冒犯你
- Yeah, I know. - I mean, no offense.
- 比利？ - 对，是我
- Billy? - Yeah, it's me.
- 我的上帝啊，见到你真好 - 姑妈，你还好吗？
- Oh, my God. Good to see you. - Aunt Kathy, how are you?
见到你真好啊，快进来
Oh, good to see you. Come on in.
听说你当上了州警，真是难以置信
They said you was in the staties. I couldn't believe it.
我被开除了，好像是我4个月前
I got kicked out, like, four months ago.
都登报了
Yeah, it was in the papers.
这么说你知道了
So you know.
你怎么会大驾光临呢？
And why are we graced with your presence?
我给你妈带了点我爸的照片来
I brought your mother some pictures of my father.
- 看那笑容 - 是我妈保存的
- Look at the smile. - My mother had them. My...
我妈…我妈去世了
My mother's dead.
对不起，真的抱歉
I'm sorry. Sorry for your troubles.
我也参加了个葬礼
I was at a funeral myself, man.
迈尔斯・卡内菲克，学校里认识的
Myles Kennefick. Knew him in school.
他还很年轻，真可怕，真可惜
He was a young guy, you know? It's terrible. It's a shame.
- 还记得那个晚上吗？真是… - 听着
- You remember that. What a night. - Listen.
我拿到…
I got, like...
- 我拿到了大概3万美金的保险金
- Like 30,000 bucks, right? Insurance money. - Yeah.
我妈去世的保险金
You know, after my mother passed and everything.
在你们这行，如果我…
In your line of work, if I gave you...
如果我给你1万的话，我能赚多少？
...like, what, say, 10,000, what could I get back?
你知道…
You know what you...
你知道我们这种时候通常会说什么吗？
You know what you usually say at these moments.
- 什么？什么？ - 别装了
- What? What? - Come on, man.
我靠，你这个混蛋
Oh, come on, you fucking moron. Come on.
你想听我亲口说？
What, you want me to say it?
我不是警察，好吗？
I'm not a cop, all right?
- 我他妈是你表弟 - 你这坏蛋
- I'm your fucking cousin. - You're bad.
你被腐蚀了，你一定是我表兄
You corrupt fuck, man. You must be my cousin.
那帮波多黎各人觉得他们什么都懂
Fucking Ricans think they know everything.
他们要是真懂 就他妈不是波多黎各人了
If they knew shit, they wouldn't be Puerto Ricans.
波多黎各猪
R is for Ricans P is for pigs
你他妈就不能闭上会嘴一会？
Would you shut the fuck up for five seconds, huh?
没错，你以前是警察
That's right. You used to be a cop.
我们在干活，你少吸点行不行？
When we're working together just limit it to two eight-balls an hour.
我们不应该在这儿干活 离伍斯特德太近了
We're not even supposed to be doing this shit this close to Worcester.
就在伍斯特德边上
This side of Worcester.
- 谁说的？ - 他说的，卡斯特罗说的
- Says who? - Says him. Says Costello.
对你来说…
God says, as far as you're...
就当是上帝说的
...concerned.
不，不，不，他不是警察 他3周前才从牢里放出来
No, no, he's no cop. He got out of the joint three weeks ago.
- 王八蛋警察 - 不，不，不
- Cunt cop. - No, no, no.
他说话不好听，不过他是好人
He talks like his shit don't stink, but he's good people.
我认识他爸
Well, I knew his father.
- 我更喜欢他叔叔杰西 - 杰西还不错
- I liked his Uncle Jackie better. - Jackie was all right.
杰西叔叔棒极了！
Uncle Jackie was excellent.
该死的意大利人
Fucking guineas.
- 敬杰西 - 杰西
- To Jackie. - Uncle Jackie.
来杯酸梅汁
Cranberry juice.
那是天然利尿剂
It's a natural diuretic.
我马子来例假时就喝这个
My girlfriend drinks it when she's got her period.
怎么？你也来例假了？
What, do you got your period?
- 靠！ - 放手！
- Fucking...! - Get off!
- 他妈的把你手拿开！ - 嘿，嘿，嘿
- Get your fucking hands off me! - Hey. Hey, hey.
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know me?
不知道
No. No.
我是来告诉你什么人能打…
Well, I'm the guy that tells you there are guys you can hit...
还有什么人不能打的
...and there's guys you can't.
这人虽说不是一点不能打他
Now, that's not quite a guy you can't hit...
但你最好还是别打他
...but it's almost a guy you can't hit.
我现在就要立个规矩
So I'm gonna make a fucking ruling on this right now:
你他妈不能打他，明白吗？
You don't fucking hit him. You understand?
好吧
Yeah, excellent. Fine. Fine, fine.
我认识你，我认识你家人
I fucking know you. I know your family.
你要是…
You make one more drug deal...
再跟你那笨蛋表兄卖毒品的话
...with that idiot fucking cop-magnet of a cousin of yours...
我就忘了你祖母曾经对我有多好
...and I'll forget your grandmother was so nice to me.
我会把你阉了的，明白了吗？
I'll cut your fucking nuts off. You understand that?
明白
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
你喝什么？
What are you drinking?
酸莓汁
A cranberry juice.
怎么了，你来例假了？
What is it, your period?
给他一杯酸梅汁
Get him a cranberry juice.
嗨，他是杰西的侄子
Hey, fuckhead, that's Jackie's nephew.
什么？你他妈“哦”什么？
What? "Oh," fucking what?
离开这吧
Get the fuck out of here.
对不起，我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
这是迪克曼警官 主要负责与卧底的联系
Staff Sergeant Dignam is our liaison to the undercover section.
对卧底工作非常了解
His undercover work is extensive.
他来给我们做下报告
He's here to give us his report. Sergeant Dignam.
我手下做卧底那几个人
Okay, my people are out there.
就像他妈的印第安人一样
They're like fucking Indians. You're not gonna see them.
除了我和昆南长官外 你们不会知道他们的行踪
You'll hear about them through me or Captain Queenan.
你们永远都不会知道卧底的身份
You will not ever know the identity of undercover people.
不幸的是，这鬼部门 比伊拉克海军的漏洞还多
Unfortunately, this shithole has more leaks than the Iraqi navy.
- 去死吧 - 我干你老婆都干腻了
- Fuck yourself. - I'm tired from fucking your wife.
- 你妈好吗？ - 她干我爸都干腻了
- How's your mother? - Tired from fucking my father.
好了，姑娘们
Good. Today, girls...
今天我要给你们说的是微处理器
...what I have is microprocessors.
你们可能已经听说了
Somebody, as you may already know, stole 20 microprocessors...
有人偷了28号公路上 迈斯公司生产的20个微处理器
...from the Mass Processor Company out on Route 128.
这种处理器放进电脑中
These are the kind they put into computers...
能准确地从几百英里外
...that could put a cruise missile up the ass of a camel...
把巡航导弹打进骆驼的屁眼
...from a couple hundred miles away.
这些塑料小东西要10几万块一个
These pieces of plastic are won'th about 100 grand apiece.
有个人在那公司干了2个月
We got a guy working for the company two months...
结果他周二偷了微处理器
...walks out the door with a box of processors on Tuesday...
订了周三去佛罗里达的机票
...has a ticket for Florida on Wednesday...
周四他的尸体就在垃圾箱里被发现了
...but on Thursday, he gets found in a Dumpster.
你知道这家伙在哪长大的？
You know where that dirtball started his life?
南波士顿
Southie projects.
- 那死人叫什么名字？ - 迈尔斯・卡内菲克
- What was his name, the departed? - Myles Kennefick.
他靠假马萨诸塞州州立大学文凭 找到这份工作
Got the job with a forged UMass transcript. UMass, Boston...
…恰好是在… - 南波士顿？
...which happens to... - South Boston?
你真是个天才 你的假文凭是从哪来的，蠢货？
Oh, you're a fucking genius. Who forged your transcript, dickhead?
这个人他老爸马特・卡内菲克 不也是爱尔兰帮成员吗？
His old man runs the Hibernian Liquor Mart. Kennefick's.
我们现在不是要讨论谁偷了微处理器
We're not here to solve the case of the missing scumbag.
卡斯特罗才是我们的重点
We're here to nail Costello.
线人报告说
All right, look. We got a guy...
卡斯特罗正准备把处理器卖到中国去
...says Costello's moving the processors to China.
他一手策划了这件事 并谋杀迈尔斯・卡内菲克
He set up the whole fucking job and popped Kennefick.
我们可不能错过卡斯特罗销赃的事情
You do not want to miss it if Costello takes a dump.
你要是多给我们情报 我们就能盯的更紧
We'd miss less if you made your informants available to us and the Bureau.
我不想追究细节 现在在卡斯特罗身边有你的卧底吗？
Without asking for too many details, do you have anyone in with Costello now?
可能有，也可能没有
Maybe. Maybe not.
可能去你妈的
Maybe fuck yourself.
我对卧底的理论就和养蘑菇一样
My theory on Feds is they're like mushrooms.
喂它们吃屎，把他们留在暗处
Feed them shit and keep them in the dark.
姑娘们工作愉快
You girls have a good day.
这人其实还不错
Normally he's a very nice guy.
只是这次会议有点反常
Don't judge him from this meeting alone.
卡内菲克夫人，我认识你儿子
Now, Mrs. Kennefick, I knew your son.
我认识迈尔斯
I knew Myles.
他比我小，但是我的学弟
He was younger than me, but he was behind me in school.
我希望能抓到那些害死他的人
I wanna get these people who did this to him.
你想帮我吗？
Would you like to help us? You wanna help catch the people...
你想帮我找到那些逼他抢劫 之后又杀了他的人吗？
...who forced your son to do a robbery and then killed him?
据称如此
Allegedly.
据称如此？
如果他是被谋杀的 那他一定做了什么错事
If he was killed, he probably did something wrong.
不是说抢劫，那不算错
But not the robbery. That's not wrong.
他还做了其它错事吗？
He did something else wrong?
亲爱的，跟你马子打个招呼
Wave to your girlfriend, honey.
你去死吧
I mean, fuck yourself.
- 你记下来了吗？ - “据称如此”还是“你去死吧”？
- Did you get that? - "Allegedly" or "fuck yourself"?
- 长见识了吧 - 这人可真怪啊
- Welcome to the neighborhood. - Different breed down here, sarge.
我要去喝杯咖啡
I need a cup of coffee.
你是上门服务吗？
You making a house call?
我工作上有见过你吗？
Have I seen you professionally?
不，但我知道你
No, no. No, I know who you are, though. I know.
那些在工作中开了枪的人…
Guys gotta use their service revolver in the course of duty...
都得和你谈谈心，聊聊天
...and then they get to come to talk to you about their feelings and whatnot.
不，不，我真的知道 你是心理健康专家
No, no, I know how it goes. You're a mental health professional.
对，我在这层有个预约…
I have an appointment on this floor.
你一定会很开心的 这层都是些怪人
Oh, well, you'll have fun. They're all frigging crazy on that floor.
- 我还要再上一层 - 噢，警察啊
- I'm one more up. - Oh, fancy policeman.
- 是啊 - 你是州警？
- Yeah, that's right, fancy. - Are you a statie?
对，另外我现在还在上法学院
Yeah, I am. I'm actually going to law school also.
上夜校吗？
Suffolk, nights?
是啊，哈佛不开夜校的 我上回查过了
Yeah, they don't run Harvard at night, last time I checked.
- 你上次是什么时候查的？ - 在我上他妈的夜校之前
- Whers the last time you checked? - Before I went to fucking Suffolk.
好啦，我是马萨诸塞州州立大学毕业的 我不想开你玩笑
Okay, listen, I went to UMass. I wasrt insulting you.
我觉得你是呢，所以你得请我吃饭
Well, I thought you were. So now you gotta buy me dinner.
也许你杀个人后 我们就能正式见面了
Maybe you can shoot someone and then see me professionally.
要是能跟你吃上饭 用他妈地冰锥戳人心脏的事我都干
I'll stab someone in the heart with a fucking ice pick if it gets me dinner with you.
不用，我是警探 我能找到你的
That's all right. I'm a detective. I'll find you.
我开玩笑的，这个我需要 名片有用
No, sorry. I'm just joking. I need the card. Card helps.
很高兴认识你，曼德琳
Nice to meet you, Madolyn.
你好，爸爸 我事先不知道跟踪你的事
Hi, Dad. I had no idea about the tail until I saw it.
我不能，当时还有其它同事在
No, I couldn't. I had the other guy with me, I couldn't...
是一辆蓝色的轿车 还有一辆白色的货车
All right, it's a blue sedan and then a white van.
货车侧面有涂鸦 上面有声音探测系统
It's fucked up with graffiti. And the van is the audio surveillance.
好的，祝你愉快
All right, have a nice day.
在这甩了他们
Cut him here.
再见
Bye-bye.
混蛋！
Jerk-ass!
巴布，我不能再这么做了
Come on, Babu. I can't do anymore. I cannot hold off.
别再让我空手而归，别这样 我只是想帮你
Don't let me go back empty-handed. Don't do this. I wanna help you.
你下周五过来，我给你钱
Come to my store next Friday. I'll give you the money.
今天就是周五，巴布 我要跟你说多少回？
This is Friday, Babu. How many times I gotta tell you?
你一直叫我巴布，我叫辛，混蛋
You keep on calling me Babu. It's Singh, motherfucker.
我只是想帮你
I'm trying to help you.
你一直说我是你的朋友 但你连我名字都他妈不知道
You keep telling me I'm your friend. You don't even know my fucking name.
如果我还想上星期那样回去 我就要挨揍了
I'm gonna catch a beating if I go back again like last week.
看到他了吗？看到这个人了吗？ 他可不想你留着钱
See this guy? You see this guy? This guy don't want you to have the money.
要是我们再回来，他就会你打爆你的头
Because he wants to come back there and squash your head.
我这还有一个顾客，你想叫我怎么办？
I have one customer sitting here. What I'm gonna do?
生意好差？你是在爱尔兰区开了这个店
Business is bad? You opened a store in an Irish neighborhood.
这些人都是狠角色，你不知道吗？
These are dirty people. Don't you know that?
我也不知道你该怎么办
Sell potatoes, I don't know what you're gonna do.
- 对不起，伙计们 - 你明白我的意思吗？
- Excuse me, gentlemen. Excuse me. Sorry. - Know what I'm saying?
你们是从普罗维登斯来的吗？
You fellas come from Providence?
这没你的事
It isn't any of your business, is it, now?
你们是不是送蛋卷的什么的？
What, are you fucking delivering cannolis or something?
你在干嘛？这是我的店！
Hey! You are killing my business, man!
靠！
Fuck!
这个国家大家都彼此憎恨吗？
What's wrong with this fucking country? Everybody hates everybody!
你给我滚！滚！
Get out of here. Get out of here!
- 你也作假释工作吗？ - 是的，我见过暴力犯罪的
- Now, you also do probation work, right? - That's right, I see violent offenders.
- 哦，坏人 - 不一定啊
- Oh, bad guys. - Not necessarily.
他们有这个，却没有我想点的菜
Yeah, they got this but they don't got duck I'orange.
你吃得还好吧？
Was your meal okay?
哦，凑合，龙虾很不错
Yeah, no, the lobster was good.
这是法国餐馆，所以我有点吃惊
I just, you know, because it was a French restaurant I was surprised.
我等你先开动呢
I'm waiting for you to make your move.
我可不知道这东西会不会动 它要是动了，我会朝它开枪的
Look, I don't know, if that thing moves, I'm gonna shoot it.
我都不知道这到底是什么
I don't even know what it is.
每天你在办公室帮人们重新找回自我
So what's it like having people find themselves...
那是什么感觉？
...in your office all day long?
被各种情绪包围 你会不会感觉很混乱呢？
Does it get messy with all those feelings flying around?
为什么？那让你很不舒服吗？
Why, does that make you uncomfortable?
- 没有，没有 - 没有？
- No, no, no. - No?
没有，没有，我现在可不是你的病人
No, no, no. No, I'm not on your couch.
你知道弗洛伊德怎么评价爱尔兰人的吗？
Well, you know what Freud said about the Irish?
当然知道
Yeah, I do.
如果你知道的话，我就会再见你
Yeah, if you actually do, I'll see you again.
谁说我还想再见你？
Who says I wanna see you again?
你不想吗？
Don't you?
- 你真应该看看你刚才的表情 - 你不想吗？
- You should see your face. - Don't you?
我当然还想再见你
Course I wanna see you again.
弗洛伊德说爱尔兰人…
What Freud said about the Irish is...
是唯一不受心理分析影响的人
...we're the only people who are impervious to psychoanalysis.
- 对，他说过 - 我知道
- Yeah, he said that. - I know he did.
你的病人里有一堆爱尔兰警察
So you're up shit's creek with a client list full of mick cops.
那我就祝你好运了
I mean, opening up? Good luck to you.
为什么你要干这行？
Why do you do it, then?
有些人确实好转了
Some people do get better.
不错
Fair enough.
有时我只想人们能忘掉他们自己的狗屁事 专心做好自己的工作
Sometimes I want people to forget their personal bullshit and do their jobs.
也包括那些罪犯？
Including the criminals?
要是他们不工作的话 你的工作也难保了
If they don't do their jobs, you don't have one.
我不担心没有工作做 到时候，只要去抓那些无辜的人就好了
I'll always have a job. I'll just arrest innocent people.
- 你有麻烦了！ - 你根本不知道我有多少麻烦
- Wait. You are trouble. - You don't know the half of it.
我现在就想逮捕你
I'll arrest you right now.
我说话算数
My word against yours.
…你猜她在婚礼上和谁跳舞呢？
- Then I see her dancing at the wedding with you-know-who.
我说“为什么不单独去拜访父母”
I say, "Why don't you go to Parents Without Partners?"
他说不带伴侣自己去看父母的， 都是一事无成的人…
He goes, "Ma, they're all losers at the Parents Without Partners," so...
我说“摩纳哥公主卡罗琳娜…”
So I say to him, "Princess Carolina of Monaco..."
斯科勒
Schuyler.
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
不认识
No.
你那天晚上和我朋友法国佬见过面
You met my friend Mr. French the other night.
他的真名就是法国佬吗？
His real name Mr. French?
不是
No.
跟我来
Come with me.
我不是警察，也不是在请你
I'm not the cops. I'm not asking you.
你要知道最好别惹 普罗维登斯的黑社会
You know something, they just do not stop having the Mafia in Providence.
这会给我惹不少麻烦
And this can cause me a lot of problems.
你惹的那些人…
Those guys you tuned up...
和普罗维登斯黑社会有联系
...they're connected down Providence.
接下来他们会做的…
What they're gonna do...
就是带些人回来把你杀了
...is come back with some guys and kill you.
只要你还活着，他们就不会放过你
Which, sure as you're born, they will do.
除非我叫他们停手
Unless I stop them.
你想要我阻止他们吗？
Do you want me to stop them?
这事我就不能自己解决吗？
Is this something I can't do personally?
让我手下搜一下你的身
I'm gonna have my associate search you.
要搜什么？我不会叫你搜的
No one's searching me. Search me for what?
看你身上有没有什么违禁物品 把鞋脱了
Contra-fucking-band. Take your shoes off.
鞋子
Shoes.
我认识你爸爸
I knew your father.
你知道他已经死了吗？
Yeah? Do you know he's dead?
很抱歉，他怎么死的？
Oh, sorry. How'd he go?
- 站起来 - 他又没抱怨什么
- Stand. - He didn't complain.
那是他的问题
Yeah, that was his problem.
谁说他有问题？
Who said he had a problem?
我刚刚说了他有问题
I just said he had a fucking problem.
他本来可以成就一番事业的
There's a man could've been anything.
你是说他一事无成？
Are you trying to say that he was nothing?
- 靠 - 我是说他在机场工作
- Fuck. - I'm saying he worked at the airport.
- 没问题 - 手臂
- He's clean. - Arm.
过来
Yeah, come on.
什么手臂？
What arm? What fucking arm?
手臂给我看看，翻过来
Show me your arm. Flip it.
在这一带见到你让我觉得很好奇
Makes me curious to see you in this neighborhood.
没问题
He's clean.
我也不想把自己的地方搞得这么乱
And if I can slander my own environment...
这让我很伤心，后悔
...it makes me sad, this regression.
加上我也不知道昆南那样的警察…
Plus, I don't know if it's beyond some fucking cop prick like Queenan...
是不是赶你出警队，让你来跟着我
...to pull you out of the staties and send you after me.
我确实不知道
I just can't know.
你也知道那个部门是干什么的
I don't know what they do in that particular department, anyway.
- 你还是警察吗？ - 不是！不是！
- Are you still a cop? - No! No!
你敢在你妈的墓前发誓 你不是警察？
Swear on your mother's grave you're still not a cop?
我他妈的绝对不是警察！
I am not a fucking cop!
你保证不再和你混蛋表兄卖毒品了？
Are you gonna stop doing coke deals with your jerkoff fucking cousin?
是的，是的是的
Yes. Yes, yes.
没事，没事了
All right, all right, all right.
你会好起来的
You're okay. You'll be all right.
这点钱拿去看手
Get your hand taken care of.
我很抱歉，但我必须这么做
I'm sorry, but it was necessary.
至于和普罗维登斯的过结
As for our problem with Providence...
不要为那些倒霉的意大利人伤心哦
...let's not cry over spilled guineas.
谁让这个爱尔兰共和军来我的酒吧的？
Who let this IRA motherfucker in my bar?
开个玩笑，你老妈还好吗？
Just kidding. How's your mother?
她快不行了
She's on her way out.
我们早晚都会到那一步的
We all are. Act accordingly.
殿下，如您所愿
Here it is, Your Highness, as ordered.
上车，我给你看点东西
Get in the car. I wanna show you something.
- 是什么让你蠢蠢欲动？ - 上车你就知道了
- What's got you all hot and bothered? - Get in the car. You'll see.
你相信他吗？
Do you trust him?
这年头…
Well, these days...
又有谁是可靠的？
...who's reliable?
他叔叔杰西就是
His Uncle Jackie was.
绝对不能相信一无所有的人
Yeah, but you can't trust a guy acts like he's got nothing to lose.
我是可靠的
I'm reliable.
阿诺，你是万里挑一
Arnold, you're one in a million.
亿，我是亿里挑一
Ten. Ten million.
你老婆呢，阿诺？
What about your wife, Arnold?
我以为她也是可靠的
Well, I thought she was.
她才不是
She wasrt.
她现在可靠了
Well, she got reliable.
你们就不能闭嘴吗？
Don't you people ever shut the fuck up?
又一个
Another county heard from.
一个就够多了，她是个大嘴巴
One too many. She got a big mouth.
接电话
Answer this for me, will you?
他们闪亮的发丝
我爱那美丽的手指
亲爱的母亲
按照侦查原则 这两个人来自普罗维登斯
The principles of detection tell me these two gentlemen came from Providence.
我是波士顿警察局的 请离开我的犯罪现场
Lieutenant Risteen, Lynn PD. I'd appreciate it you get out of my crime scene.
事实上这是我的犯罪现场 你自己好好干吧
Yeah, actually, it's my crime scene, but knock yourself out.
谢谢
Thanks.
我看到了死尸 我想我现在有很大的精神压力
I saw a dead guy. I think I'm having posttraumatic stress.
一起吃午饭吗？
Can I meet you for lunch?
好的，一会见
All right, see you then.
这案子谁负责？
Who's the lead detective?
那好办，那家伙很蠢
Good. He's a lox.
带人去吉米・帕斯家查查 当然他和这事没关系
Get the cops to look at Jimmy Pappas for the hit. He had nothing to do with it...
他也会这么说的
...and he'll say so.
你去查他的车，里面有一只枪 那枪注册的是普罗维登斯
Look in his car, you'll find the gun that did it, registered, official. Providence.
行礼箱还是前面的工具箱？
In the trunk or the glove compartment?
嗨，想见见死人吗？
Hey, you wanna see some dead guys?
这事肯定能让艾勒文队长上晚6点新闻
Hey, this will get Captain Ellerby on the 6:00 news.
难怪你这么受宠
No wonder you get ahead.
坐吧
Have a seat, Bill.
你知道约翰・列侬吗？
Do you know John Lennon?
他是林肯总统的前任
Yeah, sure, he was the president before Lincoln.
列侬说
Lennon said:
“我是艺术家
"I'm an artist.
你他妈给我根管子 我就能吹出首曲子来”
You give me a fucking tuba, I'll get you something out of it."
告诉你卡斯特罗先生
I tell you, Mr. Costello...
我更想从管子里挤出点钱来花花
...I'd like to squeeze some fucking money out of it.
好个伶牙俐齿
Smart-mouth.
不过太糟了
Too bad.
如果你允许我…
If you'll indulge me...
又去哪？
Now what?
唱诗班排练
Choir practice.
唱诗班排练…
Choir practice...
我提列侬是要告诉你…
The point I'm making with John Lennon is...
人应该能从任何东西里
...a man could look at anything...
得到些他想要的
...and make something out of it.
打个比方
For instance...
看到你我就想
...I look at you and I think:
你可以为我做什么呢？
What could I use you for?
把这个处理掉
Get rid of this.
法国佬
French.
把这个放到楼下去，谢谢
Put it downstairs. Here. Go ahead, thank you.
也许我们能干出点明堂来
Maybe we could work something out.
- 很好 - 把这个交给他老婆
- Good. - And send this to his wife.
你问那家伙用哪只手打飞机那招够狠
It was nice the way you asked the guy...
...which hand he jerked off with.
希望这个不会吓到她
I hope this don't shake Rita up.
我记得她不是那么脆弱
As I remember, she ain't that sentimental.
够快的，他已经死了？
That was quick. You think he's dead already?
我们只能用电话联络
We have to do it by phone. I won't do it...
我身上不能带着窃听器，明白？
...if I have to wear a wire. No wires. Understand?
- 你根本不知道这的情况 - 微处理器
- You don't know what this is like. - Microprocessors.
- 微什么？ - 微处理器
- Micro what? - Microprocessors.
可能我们20年后就会和中国开战
We'll probably be at war with the Chinese in 20-odd years...
现在卡斯特罗在向他们出售军事技术
...and Costello is selling them military technology.
微处理器，芯片，计算机部件
Microprocessors, chips, computer parts.
要是有人提到这方面的情况
Anybody says anything about anything like that...
及时向我们报告
...you let us know.
普罗维登斯的案子是谁犯的？
So who did the two guys from Providence?
吉米・帕斯
Jimmy Pappas.
吉米・帕斯怎么了？
What happened to Jimmy Pappas?
他这个月比较倒霉
Jimmy had a rough month.
他在监狱犯了心脏病
Jimmy had a heart attack in jail...
然后在波士顿医院被人杀了
...and then he got himself knifed at Boston City Hospital.
我想这些报纸上应该有报道
I believe it's been in the papers.
看来你对这个结果很满意
You seem quite happy with that result.
只是他妈的结果
It's a fucking result.
为什么呢？这事谁会受益？
Yeah, but cui bono? Who benefits?
管他呢，反正那案子是他犯的
Cui gives a shit? It's got a frigging bow on it.
你是块当警察的料，年轻人
I think you are a cop, my son.
- 你的执照在哪儿？ - 什么执照？
- Where's your license? - What license?
我没见过，根本没有执照这回事
I don't see none. There's no such thing as a license, of course.
看来你是真欠扁了
But you, you definitely need to have fucking one.
就算我们不来扁你，也会有别人来
If you're not being run by us, you're being run by someone else.
也就是说你给卡斯特罗先生的地盘
That means you're bringing undesirable elements...
带来了他不喜欢的东西
...into Mr. Costello's area.
我他妈只是要拿烟
I was going for my fucking cigarettes!
嘿
Hey.
嘿，他是吉米・派格斯
That's Jimmy Bags.
- 他要…我不知道 - 你到底干什么呢？
- He was rea... I don't know. - What the fuck you doing?
我缺钱啊，我付给他两千
I'm in the hole, I pay him two grand.
我给他两千，赚不到什么钱
There's no profit, I pay him two grand.
那就多赚点钱，这可是美国
Then make more money. This is America.
没钱你就等死吧 你想怎样？
You don't make money, you're a douche bag. Now what you gonna do?
- 多赚钱 - 这就对了
- Make more money. - That's the spirit!
- 靠 - 别担心
- Oh, fuck. - Don't worry about it.
那家伙根本就不需要牙
The guy don't need any fucking teeth anyway.
这虽然只是个不起眼的监视小组 但我是头儿
It's a small surveillance subunit, but it's mine.
我不想搞砸这个组 也不想别人搞砸
I didn't take this job to fuck up or let anyone else fuck up.
你们都是我亲自挑选的，都是我的人
I handpicked this group. You're my A team. Now, our prim...
嗨，队长
Hi, Captain.
这疯小子…
This crazy fuck...
…把吉米・派格斯的牙都打出来了 - 然后呢？
...knocked Jimmy Bags' teeth out. - So?
- 他要… - 他要拿他的烟
- He was... - He was reaching for his cigarettes.
你想陷害我？ 弗兰克，我不是平白无故这么做
You're gonna give me shit? It wasrt for no reason, Frank.
那家伙把手伸到衣服里
He reached into his coat.
我不知道他是想掏赌注登记本还是什么
I don't know if he's a bookie or what he's doing.
但你知道有赌注登记本的人是干什么的吧？
Well, you do know what a bookie does, don't you?
知道，交钱给你
Yeah. Yeah, he pays you.
昆南把一切都划分到特别调查组
Queenars compartmentalizing everything in SIU...
这是对的
...which is the right thing.
就个人而言，我不信任外面的人
I don't trust half the troopers out there anymore.
关键是…
Bottom line...
我们可能出问题了
...we think we might have a problem.
我们相信卡斯特罗安插了什么人在警队
We think Costello's got a rat in the state police.
- 是吗？ - 是
- Really? - Yeah, really.
我们能和昆南安插的卧底直接联系吗？
Do we have direct access to Queenars undercovers?
不，目前还不行
No, no, not presently.
但我正在想办法
But I'm working on that.
比尔，这个给你
Here, Bill, this is for you.
从今以后打这个电话到酒吧 找麦克，只找麦克
From now on, call the bar, ask for Mikey. Just Mikey.
你找麦克，是因为根本没麦克这个人
You ask for Mikey because there is no Mikey.
然后你等着，我会给你打电话
You wait. We'll call you.
- 明白吗？ - 明白
- You got that? - Yeah, I got that.
- 我没听见 - 明白
- Sorry, I didn't hear you. - I got that.
很好
Good.
嗨，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
我升职了，好
I got promoted. All right.
失陪一下
Excuse me for one second.
你知道…
You know...
如果你老爸还活着的话
...if your father were alive...
看到你跟我在一块
...and saw you here sitting with me...
他会和我商谈这件事
...let's say he'd have a word with me about this.
实际上，即使需要连杀七人才能杀了我
In fact, he'd kill seven guys just to cut my throat.
他也会做的
And he could do it...
你对你老爸有些方面还不太了解
...which is maybe something you don't know about William Costigan Sr.
- 那他从来没… - 从来没有
- So he never...? I mean, never? - No. No, no.
他有自己的原则 他对钱从来不感兴趣
He kept his own counsel. He never wanted money.
你不能跟这样的人合作
You can't do anything with a man like that.
你叔叔杰西…
Your Uncle Jackie...
如果看到我和你在一起的话 也会杀了我全家的
...he also would kill my entire fucking family if he saw me here with you.
我经常想起这些
And I think about this.
我们他妈到底在谈什么？
So what the fuck are we talking about here?
你有没有想过再回学校去？
Did you ever think about going back to school?
学校？
School?
恕我冒昧，卡斯特罗先生
With all due respect, Mr. Costello...
我不会再回去了
...school is out.
也许有天你他妈能够清醒过来
Maybe someday you'll wake the fuck up.
你好，神父
Good day, Fathers.
- 卡斯特罗先生 - 早上好，弗兰克
- Mr. Costello. - Good morning, Francis, good morning.
你还记得我们以前谈的那些淫话？
You recall our chat?
小男孩…
Little boys...
吸自己的鸡鸡，进进出出
...sucking on their peckers, et cetera and so forth...
“上帝创造了我”，这是你的准则吗？
"I am as God made me." Was that your rationale?
我提醒你一下，在这个地盘上帝说了不算
May I remind you, in this archdiocese, God don't run the bingo.
我也提醒你，骄者必败
May I remind you that pride comes before the fall.
特丽莎修女最近怎么样？
How's Sister Mary Theresa doing?
侍奉上帝之前，我和她的关系很滋润呢
We had a tasty relationship before she took her vows.
好好品尝你的鲜蛤吧，混蛋
Enjoy your clams, cocksuckers.
给他们付账
Pay them.
给那老家伙来电喝的
Get the old bombardier a drink on the house.
- 问到了什么？ - 他因持用已吊销驾照被警察扣留
- What do you got for me? - Uniform clipped him for suspended license.
他还是我们调查的对象
However, he's a subject of an open investigation...
对不止一项罪案 他是卡斯特罗的手下
More than one. He's one of Costello's.
我们正在申请搜查令 但是问不到他的地址
We're getting a warrant. Can't get an address off him.
他已经传了他的律师 不过律师还没有回电
He paged his lawyer but the lawyer hasn't called back yet.
- 谁是他的律师？ - 他也不知道名字，只有号码
- Who's the lawyer? - Didrt know the name. Just a number.
呼机号码
Beeper number.
- 律师还没来？ - 没来
- And the guy didn't show up? - No.
- 呼他了？ - 两次了
- And he beeped him? - Twice.
把你电话给我，关掉那个
Give me your phone. Turn that off.
- 干吗？ - 把摄像机关了
- What? - Turn the fucking camera off.
他不知道他律师长什么样
Give it to me. He doesn't know what the fucking lawyer looks like.
这是谁的公文包？
Whose briefcase is this? All right.
- 像吗？ - 不错
- It's off? - You're good.
下午好，菲兹先生
Afternoon, Mr. Fitzgibbons.
- 他不能这么干 - 他干了
- He can't do that. - He just did.
- 你是我的律师？ - 你觉得呢？
- You my attorney? - What do you think?
你有没有说过什么 打过什么电话，
Have you made statements or phone calls...
需要告诉我的？
...I need to be made aware of?
我呼了你
I beeped you.
按他们给我的卡片，就这些
The card they gave me. That's it.
- 就这些？ - 是的
- That's it? - That's it.
给你妈打个电话
You need to call your mother...
告诉她你今晚不能回家吃饭了
...tell her you're not gonna be home for supper.
摄像机关着，打吧
Camera's off. It's off. Call your mother.
警察正在整装准备突袭
Lookit, they're suiting up for a raid right now.
我不知道他们要去哪 但是他们知道，你也知道
I don't know where they're going, but they do. And so do you.
快打电话吧
So make the call.
听着，猪头，你用不着相信我
Lookit, fuckstick, you don't gotta trust me...
只要照我说的做
...just listen to what I'm saying to you.
妈，我不能回家吃晚饭了
Mom, I'm not gonna make it home for supper.
对不起，我有事耽搁了
Sorry, yeah, I got held up.
你先吃，不用等我了
Yeah, no, you carry on without me.
回头再聊
I'll talk to you later. Okay.
再见
Bye.
大家快走，快
Everybody out. Move.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是谁？
So who are you?
看来你得另找一个律师了 费兹先生，好运
I think you need a different attorney, Mr. Fitzgibbons. Have a great day.
我他妈什么时候能出去？
So when the fuck am I gonna get out?
查查他最后打的电话，那就是他家
All right, run the last number he called. That's his house.
不管那是什么地址 我要监视那地方
I'll swear to the judge I surveilled him there...
我们有许可
...and abra-fucking-cadabra, we got a warrant.
- 为什么用我的电话？ - 因为你没进去啊
- Why did you use my phone? - Because you didn't go in there.
这儿早晨的光线真好
The light's nice here in the morning.
想谈谈昨晚发生的事情吗？
So do you wanna talk about last night?
没什么，有的人可能太在乎这些了
You know, it's all right. Guys tend to make too big a deal out of it.
其实很平常
It's actually quite common.
我要去上班了
I gotta go to work.
你撒谎吗？
Do you lie?
为什么？你撒谎吗？
Why? Do you?
不，我问你撒谎吗
No, I'm asking if you lie.
“诚实”不是“真相”的同义词
Honesty is not synonymous with truth.
哦，你也撒谎
Yeah, you lie.
你也撒谎
You lie.
这为了做好事，谋私利…
Is it to do some good, to get somewhere personally...
还是纯粹是为了玩玩？
...or, what, just for the fuck of it?
我认为有些人这么做使事态缓和
Well, I expect that some people do it to keep things on an even keel.
哦，那你父母都是酒鬼？
So you had a parent who was a drunk.
你父母是吗？
Did you?
不是
No.
还是谈谈你吧
Let's keep it with you.
说说你的感受
Talk about how you feel.
我的感受
How I feel.
- 妈的 - 布来恩，别这样
- Fuck. - Brian, stop it.
别，求你了
No. Please. No.
不会伤害你的
Ain't gonna hurt you.
当你坐在那儿…
You sit there...
面对一个杀人狂
...with a mass murderer.
杀人狂
A mass murderer.
你的心跳加快
Your heart rate is jacked.
你的手…
And your hand...
毫不颤抖
...steady.
我在监狱里发现
That's one thing I figured out about myself in prison. My hand...
我的手不会颤抖
...does not shake.
永远不会
Ever.
别他妈在这发呆了
Wake the fuck up.
我进来的时候有个警察从这出去
There was a cop leaving when I came in.
你怎么知道他是警察？
How did you know he was a cop?
头型差，不懂得如何穿衣 整个就一流氓样
Bad haircut, no dress sense and a slight, you know, air of scumbag entitlement.
- 你也辅导警察吗？ - 这也是我的工作的一部分
- Do you see cops? - That's part of what I do.
当然，从警校里被踢出来的比较少见
I normally don't see cadets who've been kicked out of the academy.
你应该找个更好的工作
Oh, boy. You should get a better job, huh?
是吗？
Should I?
他们到这来…
So do they all come in here...
大哭一场，都是你的警察？
...and cry, your cops?
有时候是的 没错，有时候他们会大哭一场
Sometimes they do. Yeah, sure. Sometimes they cry, yeah.
如果他们有什么家庭问题，或者开了枪
If they've had trouble at home, if they've had to use their weapons...
开枪？
Use their weapons?
听我说
Let me tell you something.
他们就是为了能开枪才加入警队的
They signed up to use their weapons.
大多数 但是他们看了太多的电视
Most of them, all right. But they watch enough TV...
所以以为开过枪后都要痛哭流涕
...so they know they have to weep after they use their weapons.
再没有哪个比警察更假惺惺的了
There is no one more full of shit than a cop.
当然电视上的那些警察不算
Except for a cop on TV.
强力止痛药
我看了你的档案
I looked at your file.
你曾有过袭击他人的记录
I see that you have a record of assault.
是啊
Yeah.
在监狱是什么感觉？
So what was it like for you in jail?
你想听淋浴之类的事？ 那就是你想听的？
What, you wanna hear about the showers? Is that what you wanna hear about?
在监狱里发生什么事了吗？
Did something happen to you?
没有
No.
- 好吧，孩子，开始吧，伸开手 - 你以为你可以随便打人…
- Okay, let's do this. Come on, spread them. - Hey, you think you can pop somebody...
自己很了不起吗？ 你把吉米・帕格斯的下巴都给打碎了
...and there's a special card to play? Jimmy Bags, whose jaw you broke...
他可是波士顿警察局的卧底
...happens to work undercover for the Boston Police Department.
我他妈的都要崩溃了 我不可能一天到晚伪装成别人
I'm going nuts. I can't be someone else every day.
都已经一年了，我受够了！
It's been a year. I've had enough!
冷静点，这世上大部分人每天都在伪装 有什么大不了的
Calm down. Most people do it every day. What's the big deal?
- 我不是那种人，不是他妈的那种人 - 没错
- Well, I'm not them. I'm not them, okay? - Exactly.
你是无名之辈 你签下了合同的，记得吗？
You're nobody. You signed the papers, remember?
我们俩是这世上唯一知道你是警察的人
We're the only two people on this earth that even know you're a cop.
我们把你的档案销毁怎么样？
How about we just erase your file, huh?
我们把你的档案销毁…
How about we erase your file...
那样你就只不过是 卡斯特罗的另一条走狗而已
...and you're just another soldier for Costello...
然后你就等着被捕吧 我都不知道你犯了多少罪
...open to arrest for I don't know how many felonies. What do you say?
我要杀了你，我他妈的要杀了你！
How about I fucking kill you, huh? How about I fucking kill you!
- 他开玩笑的 - 我可没开玩笑
- That was a joke. Come on. - That wasrt a joke.
你装得像个硬汉并不代表你就真是
You play a tough guy, doesn't mean you are one...
…你个爱尔兰脓包 - 放开，快放开！
...you lace-curtain, Irish fucking pussy! - Hey, hey! Stop it! Break it up! Stop it!
- 去你妈的！ - 给我松手，这是命令！
- Fuck you, motherfucker! - Goddamn it, stop it! That's an order!
天哪，理智点
For chrissake, be smart.
要是被别人看见了，我怎么能不抓你呢？
If anybody's watching us now, how are we not supposed to arrest you?
现在上车
Come on, get in the car.
你们俩都上车
Both of you, get in the car.
你们什么时候抓抓卡斯特罗？
When are you gonna take Costello?
他干了这么多坏事，你我都清楚
What's wrong with taking him on any one...
怎么不去抓他？
...of the million felonies that you've seen him do or I've seen him do?
他杀了人，对吧？
I mean, he murdered somebody, right?
他杀了人你们都不来抓他
The guy fucking murders somebody and you don't fucking take him!
你还在等什么？ 你想看着我被碎尸后去喂穷人？
What are you waiting for? Do you want him to chop me up and feed me to the poor?
- 那就是你们想要的？ - 那可倒好了
- That what you want? - That'd stick.
你闭嘴
Will you shut up?
我们正在立案，这需要时间
We are building a case and it takes time.
你知道的
You know that.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
我告诉你，有点不对劲
I'm telling you, something's wrong.
是啊，可能是吧
Yeah, maybe.
听着，你要保持警惕，好吗？
Look, we need you to keep your ears open, all right?
我是认真的
No bullshit.
我们认为卡斯特罗 在特别调查组里安插了卧底
I think Costello's got a spy inside the Special Investigation Unit.
真的？
You serious?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
你有没有听说什么？
Have you heard anything like that?
哦，上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
再坚持一阵，孩子
Hang tight for me, kid.
再多坚持一阵
Just a little while longer.
只差这么一点了
We are this close:
好吗？
All right?
你来这想怎么样？
What do you expect coming in here?
- 我必须来 - 我知道你必须来
- I have to come here. - I know you have to come here.
既然现在你已经来了…
But now that you're here...
你想怎么样？
...what do you want?
你想听实话？
You want the truth?
安定药
Valium.
如果你撒谎，也许我就给你了
If you lied, you would have an easier time getting what you wanted.
- 那是你的工作 - 在给你开处方之前…
- What's that say about what you do? - We should have a few more meetings...
…我还需要再和你好好聊聊 - 听着，我现在惊惶失措
...before we even talk about prescriptions. - Look, I'm having panic attacks.
有天晚上我还以为我犯了心脏病 我来这的路上还吐在垃圾箱里了
Other night, I thought I was having a heart attack. I puked in a barrel on the way over.
我已经有好几周都没有睡觉了
I haven't slept for fucking weeks.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
- Is that true? - Yeah, that's true.
我说了真话，我需要药片
I said something fucking true. I want some fucking pills...
你要干什么，想封了我的档案？
...and you're gonna close my file?
- 我不会封你档案的，我… - 我以为在这里…
- I didn't say I'd close your file. No, l... - I thought I was supposed to tell...
…我应该讲真话，只有在这 - 是的，你是的
...the truth here, if only fucking here. - You are! Yes.
人们来这里放弃了隐私和自尊
A guy comes in here against every instinct of privacy, of self-reliance that he has...
而你呢？
...and what do you do?
你把他们扔到大街上去买毒品吸？ 这就是你的工作？
What do you do? You send him off on the street to score smack? Is that what you do?
太荒谬了
You're fucking ridiculous.
2片？
Two pills?
你为什么不直接给我一瓶威斯忌和一把枪
Why don't you just give me a bottle of Scotch...
让我轰掉脑袋算了？
...and a handgun to blow my fucking head off?
- 这次的狗屁心理辅导结束了吗？ - 好了，你可以走了
- Are we done with this psychiatry bullshit? - You can leave!
我受够了，我走了
What did I just put myself through? I'm out of here.
你这叫“合法威胁”，想想吧
And what if that was a legitimate threat? Think about it, fucking hotshot.
靠
Fuck.
为什么每天最后一个病人都那么麻烦？
Why is the last patient of the day always the hardest one?
因为你累了，不想认真对待
You're tired and you don't give a shit.
- 没什么不可思议的 - 听着
- It's not supernatural. - Listen.
听着，不要把我当成 为逃避坐牢而不得不见的人
Listen. You know, I'm not just somebody that you have to see or they put you in jail.
如果你觉得压力大，我会帮你的
Okay? I mean, if you're in distress, I will help you.
这是什么？
What's this?
我的名片，还有20粒安定的处方
It's my card. And a prescription for 20 lorazepam.
是吗？
Yeah?
这量足够自杀吗？
Is it enough to commit suicide?
也许，行了吧？
Maybe it is. All right? Okay?
根据你那该死的标准 我尽到我的职责了吗？
Have I done my job up to your goddamn standards?
以我的标准来说，你是典型的药品依赖
Because according to my standards, you fit the model of drug-seeking behavior.
太糟了，如果你不喜欢我最初的临床反应
You know, and too damn bad if you don't like my initial clinical reaction.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会把你转给另一位心理医生的
I'm transferring you to another counselor.
- 很好 - 好吧
- Good. - Okay.
想一起喝杯咖啡吗？
So you wanna get a cup of coffee?
搬到这来，来个人把它搬到这来
Bring it in here, please. Would somebody bring it in?
进来
Come on in.
本次行动的目标是微处理器交易
Our target is a major transaction of microprocessors.
是的
Yes, those.
我不知他们是什么，你们也不知道 管他呢
I don't know what they are, you don't know what they are. Who gives a fuck. Cash.
钱，大量的现金将在这栋楼里转手
Lots of cash is gonna change hands inside a building...
我们已经做好视频监视
...that we have under AV surveillance close-by.
我知道摄像头位置不算好 但我们时间有限
I know this location is not the best, but we had very little time to set up.
- 你们知道这事吗？ - 不知道
- You guys know anything about this? - No.
苏利文警官的小组将负责 辨认他们的身份，监听电话
Sullivars team will ID the bad guys and listen in on the phones.
我们先不行动
Our unit will not take action.
我再说一遍，我们先不行动 直到昆南警官的卧底…
I repeat, not take action, until a man that Captain Queenan has inside...
…确认交易进行才行动，明白？
...verifies the transaction. Are we clear?
有什么问题吗？没？ 这就是我们要抓的
Anybody? Any questions? No? This is who we're after.
我们已经盯了他很久了
We've been after this cocksucker for a long time, and tonight...
今晚就能将他逮捕 开始工作吧
...we are going to get him. Let's go to work.
你们去弄清楚我们到底要做什么
All right, you guys find out what we're doing and get on it.
对不起，这么迟才通知你
Sorry to get you last-minute, but things leak.
这条消息是昆南手下的卧底提供的
This lead came from Queenars undercover guy.
我要去抽烟，你不抽烟对吗？ 怕得癌吗？去死吧
I'm gonna smoke. You don't smoke? One of those fitness freaks, huh? Go fuck yourself.
- 嗨，爸爸 - 嗯
- Hi, Dad? - Yes.
工作上有点事情
Yeah, something big came up at work.
- 我晚上不能回来吃饭了 - 太糟了
- I'm not gonna be home for supper. - Too bad.
你妈忙活了一天
Your mother worked all goddamn day.
那我们就不等你和你朋友自己吃了
We'll just have to sit down without you and your friends.
不，我朋友还是要来的
Oh, no, my friends are still coming.
我们明天一起吃午饭吧
So we'll just... I'll just see you for lunch instead tomorrow.
你妈妈会很高兴的
Your mother will be proud.
好的，谢谢，老爸
All right, thanks, Pop. Bye.
一切都准备好了
The readiness is all.
你熟悉那群人，你负责吧
You know the players. Call the game.
谢谢
Thank you.
你准备好了吗
- You ready? - Is your highness...
殿下是要工作之前带我去忏悔 和我上床还是什么？
...gonna drop me off at confession before work, or fuck me, or what?
你要和那些狗屁神父忏悔什么？
What have you got to confess to that anointed pederast?
忏悔的保密，这年头…
A confessional seal, these days...
我也不能保证
...I'm not so sure.
很简单，他操作摄像头 你识别他们的身份
He'll operate the cameras. You ID the guys and log them.
所有检测的手机信号都会在那上面显示
All cell-phone signals are under surveillance...
多亏联邦调查局朋友的帮助
...through the courtesy of our federal friends over there.
爱国行动，爱国行动！ 我喜欢，我喜欢
Patriot Act, Patriot Act. I love it, I love it, I love it.
看着这个
Keep an eye on this one.
别用电话
发送
好了，目标出现
All right, here we go.
那个是卡斯特罗，法国佬
There's Costello. Mr. French.
菲兹和迪兰亨特
There's Fitzy, Delahunt...
还有新人比尔・卡斯提根
...and the new guy, Billy Costigan.
别用电话
时间是10:46
Time is 10:46.
好了，把你们的手机都关掉
All right, turn off your cell phones.
菲兹拿着货，大家检查一下武器
Fitzy's got the chicken. Check your weapons.
- 我们有个盲点 - 为什么？
- We have a blind spot. - Why do we have a blind spot?
我们只有2小时的时间安装摄像头
We had two hours' notice. Two hours.
- 你以为我们是国家航空太空总署？ - 这我可没想过
- Fuck you think this is, NASA? - It never crossed my mind.
- 后面装了摄像头吗？ - 什么后面？
- Have you got a camera in the back? - What back?
- 最近好吗，兄弟？ - 很好，卡斯特罗先生
- How you going, Robert? - Good, Mr. Costello.
我想告诉你他们至少两人带了机枪
I wanna tell you, at least two of these gents have machine guns.
有没有搞错啊
我左等右等你都不来
我都想走了
这位先生是政府的人啊，老大
如果被人捉到，他就死定了
是不是都给人杀死才好啊，大哥
这位先生是中国政府官员 他现在吓坏了
He's from the Chinese government. He's scared shitless.
政府官员，害怕？
Government man. Scared.
我很担心你们这些中国人，居然自作聪明
I'm concerned about a Chinaman who thinks it's wise...
带着自动武器来做商业交易
...to come to a business transaction...with automatic weapons.
为他自己好 告诉李小龙和他手下的空手道们
For his own good, tell Bruce Lee and the Karate Kids...
我们都没带自动武器
...none of us are carrying automatic weapons.
因为在这个国家
Because here, in this country...
有枪不代表你牛x
...it don't add inches to your dick.
抓到就判重刑
You get a life sentence for it.
快点把机关枪收起来
快点收起来
收枪
把枪放下
如果我们像国土安全部那些笨蛋有钱 我就能…
If we had some Homeland Security money like some douche bags I could mention...
- 有电话吗？ - 他们把手机关了
- Any calls? - They turned off their cell phones.
随机搜索从那个区域打出的电话
Search randomly for calls made from the area.
有807个电话
Eight hundred and seven phones are live in this area.
缩小区域
Then narrow the area.
开着手机的就是你们要抓的
What you see there for service is what you're gonna get.
他们为什么把手机都给关了？
Why did they turn their phones off?
- 等等，还有一部手机开着 - 在哪？
- Wait. There's still one phone up. - Where?
买家在那
The buyers are there.
和你卧底直接联系会更方便
You know, direct contact with your guys would have its advantages.
不能和我的人联系
Not to my guy.
难以置信 到底是谁他妈的装的摄像头？
This is unbelievable. Who put the cameras in this place?
你他妈是谁？
Oh, who the fuck are you?
我是尽职干活的人 你一定是那个不尽职的了
I'm the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.
如果这些中国佬 想在本世纪收复台湾的话
If these Chinks wanna nuke Taiwan any time in this century...
他们最好麻利点，给我那100万
...they'd better shape up and show me 1 million dollars.
这是我们这个国家的规矩
What we generally do, in this country...
一手…
...is one guy...
交钱
...brings the items...
一手…
...and the other guy...
交货
...pays him.
如果没钱
No "tickee"...
就别做买卖
...no laundry.
去，费兹
Go ahead, Fitz.
车子开了，看到有人出来了吗？
Cars are moving, but did you see anybody come out?
告诉我这车不是空的
Please tell me those cars aren't empty.
快告诉我这车不是空的！
I mean, Jesus fucking Christ, please tell me that those Chinamers cars aren't empty!
他们不知道我们有海军
They didn't figure we had a navy.
你在后面装摄像头了没有？
Did you put a camera in the back?
我能和你谈谈吗？
Can I talk to you for a second, please?
蠢货！
You stupid fucking hard-on!
你全搞砸了！
You fucked this whole thing up!
你都干了什么？放开我！
What the fuck did you do, you cocksucker? Let go of me!
我要揪下你的胳膊，塞进比屁眼！
I'm gonna rip your fucking arm off and shove it up your fucking ass!
我们见个面吧，亲爱的 我给你买冰淇淋
Why don't we meet? Let me buy you an ice cream.
我要走了，除非你叫昆南接电话
I'm getting on a plane unless you put Queenan on.
昆南去参加葬礼了 现在我值班，你冷静一下
Queenan had a funeral to go to. This is my shift. Calm down.
为什么我他妈不能走，嗯？
Why shouldn't I get on a fucking plane, huh?
见面？你真的想要我死吗？
Meet up? You actually want me dead?
你的部门里有内鬼，这是事实
Look, there is a rat in your unit. That is a fact, all right?
- 昆南在哪？ - 他不在
- Where's Queenan? - He's not here.
他们知道你们在楼里装了摄像头 他们什么都知道
They knew you had cameras in the building. They knew everything.
消息是内部的人泄漏的，这是千真万确 你得把他揪出来
There is a leak from the inside. It's real. Man, smoke him out.
怎么揪？ 你这连警校都没毕业的天才给我说说看
Yeah, how do we do that, Mr. Genius-Who- Didrt-Even-Graduate-From-the-Academy?
提供假情报 只你把情报透露给特别调查组的人
Disinform. Let it slip to SIU that you have a sealed wiretap warrant...
说你们在卡斯特罗的屋子里装了窃听器
...for Costello's apartment. Don't tell anyone in our division, but tell SIU.
顺藤摸瓜 看看我能否抓住他
Flush it down the pipe, see if it comes out on my end.
这就是我们首先要做的 我们要缩小范围
That's what we do first. Narrow it down.
- 他妈的昆南在哪？ - 他不在
- Where the fuck is Queenan, huh? - He's not here.
你要是想碰头，或是有新情况再打给我
You wanna meet up or you got something real, call me back.
从根本上改变你的生活
- Changing your life radically.
改变一切，对吗？
Change anything. Right? Change everything.
- 对吗？ - 对
- Right? - Yeah.
你和这人交往多久了？
How long you been with this guy?
- 我男朋友？ - 是
- My boyfriend? - Yeah.
- 四个月，快四个月了 - 四个月
- Four months. Almost four months. - Four months.
你爱他吗？
Do you love him?
我们俩都很认真的
It's a pretty serious relationship, yeah.
很认真
It's very serious.
他是不是也像我这样怪？我只是好奇
Is he a headcase like me? I'm just curious.
不如我
No more than I am.
我知道这是一段认真的感情
I know that it's a serious relationship.
感情总是会有起伏的
I know there are ups and downs. Right?
有疑惑，有问题
People have doubts and problems.
也许称不上是问题，但是会有疑惑
Well, not problems, but doubts.
如果他看到我们在一起，你会怎么办？
What would you do if he was standing right there and he saw us?
我会撒谎 是的，我会撒谎
I would lie. Yeah, I would lie.
为了保持事态平稳，对吧？
You know, to keep things on an even keel, right?
我们谈过这个的
Right? We talked about that.
- 早安 - 早安
- Morning. - Good morning.
想吃法式甜圈吗？
Want a French doughnut?
好啊
Yeah.
- 我能看吗？ - 嗯
- Hey, can I lookit? - Yeah.
当然
Sure.
- 我要把这个拿走 - 什么？
- All right, we're not having this out. - What?
你没见过我小时候的照片吧？
You don't see any pictures of where I came from.
我尊重你的现在
Look, I respect who you are...
只是这些不能放在客厅
...just, you know, not in the living room.
可能会有客人来访
We might have company.
- 来访？ - 是的，来访
- Company? - Yeah, company.
- 你为什么为政府做事？ - 为什么不呢，你也是
- Hey, now, why do you work for the state? - Why not? You do.
你的工作埋没了你的才能，你这么辣
No, what you do. The degrees and all, everything you got. You're hot shit.
是吗？
Yeah?
为什么要做心理辅导？
So why do you make as much as a guidance counselor?
因为我相信公众服务
Because I believe in public service.
你在耍我吗？ 很可笑吗？
So now you're gonna fuck with me? So now you're gonna be ridiculous, huh?
- 别跟我来这套，别... - 嘿
- No, don't start with me. Don't... - Hey.
讨厌的电话，能不能停下！
Ah, fuck with the fucking phone! Stop it!
- 电话 - 别管电话
- The phone. - Forget the phone.
不，不，接电话
Get it. Answer it. Answer it.
这是你新家的第一个电话
This is your first phone call in the new house.
你住在这里,你是住户了
You live here now. You're a resident.
梅尔 苏利文办公室
Mayor Sullivars office.
让科林接电话
Put Colin on the phone right now.
哦,天哪,对不起
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
怎么了？
What?
这个人好像...
I think it's a guy with...
- 有喉癌 - 喂
- It's like a cancer guy. - Hello.
你的电话是他妈怎么回事?
What the fuck is it with you and your phone, huh?
我…工作上的事
Something for work.
没事没事，手机没电了 我事先不知道...
Hey. Nothing, nothing, nothing. It went dead. I don't know, I get...
刚才是那个小妞接的电话？
Was that that shrink cunt that answered the phone?
我说过她要... 搬进来和我住一起
Remember I told you that we were... She was gonna move in?
- 对 - 她搬进来了
- Yeah. - She moved in.
- 你最好把一切都搞定了 - 嘿,上次要不是我事先通知你
- You better get organized, quick. - Hey, last time I checked, I tipped you off...
你早就进监狱了
...and you're not in jail.
- 你在听我说吗？ - 是的
- Are you listening to me? - Yeah.
你想要那个女人吗?
Do you like Little Miss Thing sucking on your cock?
当然
Yes. Yes, I do.
那就好好干
So earn it.
我有种感觉...
I'm getting the feeling...
...我的手下有警察的卧底
...we got a cop in my crew.
我知道 我也感觉到了
Yeah, I know, I'm kind of getting that feeling too.
是你们的人
He's one of yours. Inside.
有什么发现吗？
Have you seen anything?
我无权查看昆南的卧底档案 只有他和迪克曼两个人知道卧底的情况
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
- 我正在尽力 - 尽力?
- Doing my best. - Your best?
你以为我们是做服装买卖的？
What do you think we're in, the fucking haberdashery business?
听着，弗兰克，如果你不放轻松...
Look, Frank, if you don't relax...
听着，弗兰克，如果你不放轻松 我就不能放松,我现在需要的是
If you don't relax, I can't relax. All right? Now, what I need you to do...
昨晚和你一起的那些手下的信息
...get me information on the people with you last night. Your crew.
给我他们的社会保险号码...
Get me social-security numbers, get me...
给你？给你？ 你他妈到底给谁干活?
Get you? Give you? Who the fuck do you work for?
好了…弗兰克… 好了，对不起
All right, all right. Frank, Frank, Frank. All right. I'm sorry.
请您帮我搞到 他们的社会安全号，出生日期
If you could, please. What I need are SS numbers, DOBs...
所有能证明那些人来历的资料
...just all the pedigree information so I can run it on my end and we can ID the prick.
你给我搞来那些信息
If you can get me that information...
我就能搞定的
...I can... We're gonna handle it. I can handle it.
冷静，不然你要尿裤子了
Calm down, or you'll shoot in your pants.
我会给你你要的资料
I'll get you the records and whatnot.
但是听我说，孩子 不要让我失望...
But listen to me, son. Don't disappoint me on this...
不然的话...
...or some other guy will be putting their fat cock...
就会有别人来搞你女朋友了
...up Little Miss Freud's ass.
你还好吗，弗朗西斯？
How are you, Francis?
- 我妈叫我弗朗西斯 - 我知道
- My mother called me Francis. - I know she did.
我还知道你爸叫你肿瘤
And your father called you the tumor.
那你爸怎么叫你，查理？
And what did your father call you, Charlie?
哦，我忘了,你根本就没老爸
Oh, yeah, I forgot. He wasrt around.
你老板做过喉头切除手术?
You have a boss that has a laryngectomy?
不，那只是我的一个手下
No, no, no. That was a guy who works for me.
你骗我
You're lying to me.
不尽然
Not exactly.
你把那些真的微处理器怎么样了，弗兰克？
What did you do with the real microprocessors, Frank?
微处理器
Microprocessors.
噢，对了，我听说了
Oh, yeah.
你在边境抓到了什么中国政府官员
I heard the story. You arrested some Chinese government guys...
那人身上带着几块电灯插座
...at the border carrying some light sockets or something.
我真想把你那张假笑的脸给撕下来
I can't wait to wipe that fucking smirk off of your face.
你这混蛋就配给我擦屁股
Wouldrt you rather wipe my ass for me?
我工作中一些事情不能告诉你
There are certain parts of my job that I'm not gonna be able to talk to you about.
我也不容许有任何东西威胁到我们的调查
And I cannot allow you to jeopardize an ongoing investigation...
还有你的生命
...or your life.
真的，有些事你不会想知道
No, really, there are things you don't even wanna know about.
好，你说清楚就好
Okay, then just say that.
好的，我会的
All right, I will.
搬家的人来了
Oh, that's the movers.
这么说你还想住在这？
Yeah, you still wanna stay?
- 是的 - 是吗?
- Yes. - Yeah?
来了! 来的真不是时候
Come on, I'm coming! It's the worst timing.
我会抓到你的
I'm gonna get you.
你要是抓得到我早抓了
If you could've, you would've.
不过我猜你大概喜欢慢慢来
But I guess you like to go at your own pace.
失陪了，我和天使有约
Excuse me. Got a date with some angels.
弗兰克
Frankie.
Frankie!
你妈妈已经原谅我了
Your mother forgives me.
你带着钱下车干什么去了？
You take off an armored car at the mall.
是去给那些普罗维登斯 意大利佬送钱去了吗？
What the fuck, you pay guineas in Providence?
- 我没有! - 那你干什么去了？
- Fucking now I do! - What the fuck do you do?
我得在卡斯特罗把我 卖给联邦调查局前把钱给他 他总是这么干的
I gotta pay Costello for him to trade me to the FBI? Because that's what he does.
联邦调查局？你他妈的在说什么？
FBI? What the fuck you talking about, FBI?
天啊，弗兰克在外面吗？
My God, is that French out there?
你说的联邦调查局到底怎么回事？
What the fuck did you just say about the FBI?
没什么，我吸毒兴奋瞎说的
Forget what I said. I'm fucking high.
不管你那弱智的脑袋是怎么想的...
Whatever may be going on in that very fucking poor...
我是不会伤害你的
...very limited brain of yours, I am not gonna hurt you, all right?
- 再说一遍你刚说的话 - 没什么
- Just tell me what you fucking said. - Forget it.
我吸毒兴奋了,我兴奋的飘起来了 刚才那些话都是瞎说的
I'm high. I'm fucking high. I must be high. I'd never say what you thought I said.
去死!
Fuck!
你刚才他妈到底说什么了！
Now, what the fuck did you just fucking say?
为什么他从没被抓过？ 卡斯特罗是受联邦调查局保护的线人
Why do you think he never gets busted? Costello's a protected FBI informant.
他会把你们都出卖的
He'll trade you out.
我还以为中了枪我会休克过去
I thought I was supposed to go into shock.
没有，我现在好痛！
I'm not in shock. It fucking hurts!
疼死了!
It fucking hurts!
嗨，是我
Hey. It's me.
- 你来这干什么？ - 过来
- What are you doing here? - Come here.
卡斯特罗把人卖给联邦调查局
Costello's giving people up to the FBI.
- 联邦调查局? - 他给联邦调查局工作
- The FBI? - He is giving information to the FBI.
他是他妈的被保护的线人
He's a protected fucking informant.
他们不是总想弄成个联邦案件 却总没成功？
I mean, aren't they always trying to make it a federal case and it never gets made?
到后面去，我来开门，快去
Go around the back. I'll open the door. Go on.
- 这是冰水 - 谢谢
- Here's some ice water. - Oh, thanks. Thanks.
那是我儿子，帕特里克
That's my son, Patrick.
- 他在圣母大学读书 - 是吗?
- Goes to Notre Dame. - Oh, yeah?
我太太睡觉了，她给我留了晚饭 你要吃点吗？
My wife's asleep but she left some supper out. You want something to eat?
不，谢了
No. No, thanks.
吃点晚饭，我们到厨房里谈
Yeah, come on, man. You have some supper. We'll talk in the kitchen.
来吧
Come on.
想来点儿白粉吗？
You want some coke?
给你
There it is.
在你麻木之前不要动啊
Don't move till you're numb.
进来
Come on. Get inside.
老板要你的真实姓名...
Boss wants your real name...
你的社会保险号，银行帐号
...your social and license number, your bank account numbers.
我没银行帐号
I don't have a bank account.
- 我也喜欢现金交易 - 他要干什么，给我们开养老帐号？
- I'm a cash business myself. - What's he doing, setting up IRAs?
少废话，把表填了 你的真名和帐号
Just fill the fucking paper in. Your real name and all your account numbers.
然后我们在这里等着
Then we wait here.
- 开玩笑吧 - 没有
- You're shitting me. - No, I ain't.
把表放进去
Put the forms in there.
我不知道怎么拼“市民”
I don't know if this is how you spell "citizens."
管他呢,你知道吗?
But fuck it, you know?
不对，我来吧
No, no, no. Come here.
你他妈是不是弱智啊？
What, are you fucking retarded or something?
肯定不是那么写
That ain't fucking right.
开玩笑吧?
Are you kidding me?
看这个,看
Look at this. Look.
市民
"Citizens." Look.
比尔，他说让我们呆在这儿
Billy, he said to stay here.
我他妈还要回去吸毒呢
Yeah. I'm not sitting here without a tetanus shot.
你他妈去哪儿？
Where the fuck are you going?
我不想呆在这，好吗？ 告诉他我说的
I'm not staying, all right? You can tell him I said that.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
- 外面雨很大 - 是啊
- It's pouring out there. - Yeah.
听着...
Look...
- 如果你觉得不合适,我... - 不
...if this is inappropriate, l... - No.
不，没什么不合适的 你又不是我病人
No, it's not inappropriate. You're not a patient.
你是搬出还是搬进？
So you moving out or you moving in?
租约还剩三周
I've still got three weeks left on the lease.
那是我
That's me.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
- 你是不是举棋不定了？ - 没有
- Hedging your bets? - No. No.
你得选择
You have to choose.
- 你得做出... - 决定
- You have to make a... - A decision.
决定，然后就要坚持你的选择
A decision. And, you know, you have to stick by what you choose.
- 你要... - 搬到男朋友那里?
- You have to... - Move in with your boyfriend?
否则的话...
Yes. Otherwise it's...
我知道,我知道,我知道
Oh, I know, I know. I know.
我得说，你这种受伤的样子 现在有点让我害怕
I have to say your vulnerability is really freaking me out right now.
是真的吗？
Is it real?
我想是吧
I think so.
你没养猫
You don't have any cats.
恩
No.
我喜欢这样
I like that.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我们都相信卡斯特罗...
We are all convinced that Costello has at least...
在特别调查组里至少安插了一个内鬼
...one mole inside the Special Investigations Unit.
你要调查所有的人
You will investigate everybody and anybody.
这可不是什么好差事啊
Well, that's not exactly a dream job for a cop.
在所有的候选人里 你的档案完美无缺
We looked at all possible candidates. You have an immaculate record.
有些人不信任这种完美的人 但是我信任
Some people don't trust a guy with an immaculate record. I do.
我也是完美的人
I have an immaculate record.
婚礼的事准备的怎么样了？
How is your wedding coming along?
不错，她是医生
Great. Great. She's a doctor.
- 厉害 - 是
- That's outstanding. - Yeah.
婚姻是人生重要的一环
Marriage is an important part of getting ahead.
至少人们会知道你不是同性恋 而且你本人看上去也更可靠些
Lets people know you're not a homo. Married guy is more stable.
人们看到你的戒指就会想 至少还有个人能忍受这个混球
People see the ring, think at least someone can stand him.
女人看到你的戒指,立刻就知道你至少有点儿钱 而且你的老二还好用
Ladies see the ring, they know you must have some cash and your cock must work.
是好用,还能加班呢
Yeah, it's working. Overtime.
- 很高兴听到这个 - 谢谢
- I'm glad to hear that. - Thank you.
跟着信封
来啊,来啊
Be dirty, be dirty.
哦...
Yeah...
妈的，你有毛病啊?
Frank. The fuck is wrong with you?
- 你不喜欢吗？ - 我差点就开枪了
- See anything you like, Col? - I almost fucking shot you.
- 你不喜欢自虐吧？ - 坐下
- You're not indulging in self-abuse, are you? - Sit down.
我希望你不会背叛我
I hope you're not turning into one of them sob sisters wants to get caught.
你还承受的住吗？
You're not cracking up, are you?
- 我不会崩溃的 - 选这么个地方见面...
- I don't crack up. - Pick a place like this...
太容易被警察发现了
...where any cop could see you. Jesus.
如果这主意很糟，为什么你还来?
If this is such a fucking bad idea why'd you show up?
因为这里是我的地盘
I own the place.
什么？我他妈的太吃惊了
Why am I not fucking surprised?
- 我有些事要告诉你... - 你被分配了其他任务
- All right, lookit, I gotta tell you... - You're getting reassigned. I know.
你他妈怎么知道的？
How the fuck do you know that?
- 他们让你干什么？ - 弗兰克
- Where'd they put you? - Hey, Frank.
我要查出"我自己"
I gotta find myself.
快告诉我，小子
You're telling me, sonny boy.
我得找出你在警局里安插的内鬼
I gotta find the guy you got in the department.
大家都自顾不暇 再加上你自己就是那个内鬼...
With everybody looking up their own ass and you looking for yourself...
我打赌到头来他们还是什么也查不到
...I put my money on nobody finds nothing.
我知道，但是弗兰克，为了我 你现在要低调行事
I know, but, Frank, lookit. For me, you gotta lay low.
- 就现在 - 科林...
- Right now. - Collie...
低调行事不是我的风格
...laying low is not what I do.
没错，你厉害，什么都不怕
All right, fucking Big Daddy Frank. Fucking perfect.
如果你不听我的劝告，
What good am I to you if you don't listen to me?
那要我干什么？
What good am I if you don't listen?
识别疑犯
昆南现在把他的部门和我们的分开
Queenan is compartmentalizing. He's splitting everything up.
他很聪明，这点你清楚
He's fucking smart. You know this.
弗兰克，我能找到内鬼 但是你要让我放手干
I can get the rat. You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
好吧
Okay.
不过科林,我不想再提醒你...
But Colin, I hope I won't have to remind you...
如果你还找不到内鬼的话
...that if you don't find that cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
到头来最先倒霉的可不是我
...most likely, it won't be me who suffers for it.
何必一再提醒我这点呢？
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
难道这对我现在的工作有任何帮助吗？
Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
弗兰克，你得相信我
Frank, you gotta trust me.
好吗？相信我，弗兰克
All right? Just trust me, Frank.
要是需要撒谎的话 你知道我他妈很在行的
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
好吗？
Right?
也许是因为我玩女人太容易了
Maybe because it's always been so easy...
我就不明白为什么 有人要在电影院里玩手淫
...for me to get cunt that I never understood jerking off in a theater.
妈的
Christ.
谁知道究竟什么事情容易呢？
Who knows what's easy?
科林，我相信你能办好这件事
Colin, I know you'll take care of business.
妈的！
Shit!
干！
Fuck.
进行拘捕
嗨，你好吗？
Hey, how you doing?
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, Darlene, hi.
- 我走了 - 再见
- That's it for me. - Yeah, see you.
祝你愉快
Have a good one.
我闻到了内鬼味
I smell a rat.
妈的
Jesus Christ.
你有女朋友吗？
You got a girlfriend?
没有
No.
为什么问我这个，有什么问题吗？
No, no. Why, what does that matter?
那要看情况了
It depends.
我相信你已经知道...
I'm sure by now you know...
我的手下里有卧底
...I got an informer in my outfit.
条子...
Cop.
或者是州警 我也不太清楚
Staties, Boston Police Department, I'm not sure.
妈的
Jesus Christ.
你肯定不是联邦调查局？
Are you sure it's not the FBI?
不是联邦调查局
It ain't the FBI.
前妻
Ex-wife.
女友
Old girlfriend.
还有愚蠢
Or stupid.
干我们这行的最怕这几样
That is what brings you down in this business.
愚蠢？
Stupid, huh?
至少我不在此列
Well, I guess that leaves me out.
要是这种事发生在以前 我早就把所有人都宰了
You know, past days, situation like this, I kill everybody.
所有我的手下
Everybody who works for me.
弗兰克，我们的人...
Right. You know, Frank...
那些人...
...I look around at your other guys...
他们都杀人不眨眼，对吧？
I mean, they're all murderers, right? Right?
我想，我能不能也像他们一样？
And I think, "Could I do murder?"
我所知道的只是
And all I can answer myself is:
我和他们又有什么分别呢？
"What's the difference?"
留给上帝发落吧
Give them up to the Almighty.
我想说的就是
You see, that's my point, you know?
指责我一次，我还能容忍
You accuse me once, I put up with it.
指责我两次...
You accuse me twice...
我退出不干了
...I quit.
你要是想让我胆战心惊...
You pressure me to fear for my life and I will put a fucking bullet in your head...
我二话不说就崩了你的头，懂吗？
...as if you were anybody else. Okay?
你有事要问我吗？
You got something you wanna ask me?
你都70岁了，弗兰克 我只是说
Look, you're 70 years old, Frank. I'm just saying, okay?
总有人会出卖你的
One of your guys is gonna pop you.
- 会有人的 - 我知道
- One of your guys is gonna pop you. - Yeah, yeah.
指控你搞毒品勾当 你到底在搞什么？
As for running drugs, what the fuck are you doing?
你根本就不缺钱花 但你就像他们的眼中钉肉中刺
You don't need the money or the pain in the ass. And they will catch you.
自从我三年级的抢了同学的牛奶钱后
I haven't needed the money...
我就不缺钱花了
...since I took Archie's milk money in the third grade.
说实话，我也不需要女人
Tell you the truth, I don't need pussy anymore, either.
但是我喜欢
But I like it.
我想说的是，比尔...
Point I'm making here is, Bill...
现在我这有内鬼...
...I got this rat...
恶心，该死的内鬼
...this gnawing, cheese-eating, fucking rat...
这使我产生了置疑
...and it brings up questions.
比尔你是新来的
You know. See, Bill, like, you're the new guy.
还记得我们刚才说的前妻女友什么的吗
Girlfriend...
让你写号码那天，为什么你不呆在酒吧里？
Why don't you stay in the bar that night I got your numbers?
社会安全号
Social-security numbers.
- 是的 - 所有人的号码
- Yeah. - Everybody's fucking numbers.
这就是你想要问的?
Is there something that you just wanna go ahead and ask me?
我他妈现在就回答你
Because I'll give you the fucking answer, all right?
看着我，弗兰克
Frank, look at me. Look at me.
我他妈的不是内鬼，懂吗？
I'm not the fucking rat. Okay?
我不是那个内鬼！
I'm not the fucking rat.
这么说你也认为有内鬼了？
Start with you agree there is a rat.
是你说的有内鬼
You said there is one, all right?
我这么说是因为 我知道你对这种事情很在行
I base most of what I do on the idea that you're pretty good at what you do.
很好,很好
Sure. Sure, Will.
你，威廉，你会怎么做？
You, William. What would you do?
弗兰克，这里有多少人...
Frank, how many of these guys...
有资格坐上你的位置？
...have been with you long enough to be disgruntled?
你仔细想想 你给的钱不多
Think about it. You don't pay much, you know.
你给的钱只够买棺材的
It's almost a fucking feudal enterprise.
问题是，这是唯一的问题...
The question is, and this is the only question...
谁觉得他比你有能耐，可以取代你？
...who thinks that they can do what you do better than you?
唯一能取代我的人就是我
The only one who could do what I do is me.
其他能取代我的都死了
Lot of people had to die for me to be me.
你想取代我吗？
You wanna be me?
我也许可以
I probably could be you. Yeah.
这我知道
Yeah, I know that much.
但我不想取代你，弗兰克
But I don't wanna be you, Frank.
我不想
I don't wanna be you.
王冠难戴啊
"Heavy lies the crown" sort of thing.
没错
Yeah.
- 弗朗西斯 - 我要走了，别忘了把警报...
- Francis. - I'm out of here. You'll set the alarm...
- 好的,圣诞节见 - 好吧,晚安
- Yeah, all right. I'll see you at Christmas. - All right. Good night.
为什么大家喜欢餐厅？
You know what I like about restaurants?
因为有吃的？我不知道
The fucking food? I don't know. What?
看别人吃饭你能学到很多东西
You learn a lot watching things eat.
有艘船货要到格拉斯特
There's a boat coming up Gloucester.
具体情况法国佬会告诉你
French will give you all the details. Don't forget.
吃点东西吧，看在上帝份上
Eat something, for Christ's sake.
以后叫你做什么你就做什么，明白了吗？
In the future, I tell you to do a thing, you fucking do it. You got that?
明白了,好的
I got it. Okay?
对不起...
Excuse me...
- 不好意思，法国佬，我的... - 好的，弗朗西斯
...French, I forgot my... - Okay, Francis.
香烟
...cigarette.
吃点东西吧
Eat something.
有什么问题吗?
Problem?
是，我确实有点问题 我才是主管，你少来这掺合
Yeah, I got a problem. I run rat fucks like you, okay? I don't like them.
哪天你不想升官了，记得告诉我一声
The day you wouldn't take a promotion, let me know.
如果你能处理好的话 根本就不会叫我来
If you'd taken care of this I wouldn't be here.
- 你去死吧，臭狗屎 - 我要你那个卧底的身份
- Fuck yourself, you piece of shit. - I need the identity of your undercovers.
去死吧 你还没到那个级别
Blow me. Not literally. Unfortunately, there's no promotion involved for you.
混蛋
Fucking prick.
- 嗨，队长 - 瞧瞧，这不是明星来了吗
- Hi, captain. - Look who's here. The prom queen.
- 大家好像都不喜欢我 - 你想怎么样呢？
- They are not happy with me. - What do you expect?
大家都知道你被分配到这里 查卡斯特罗的卧底
Everybody knows you've been assigned here to find Costello's rat.
他们和你一样想揪出那个家伙
They want to find the leak as much as you do.
两天前,我的卧底差点就查出 卡斯特罗卧底的身份
Like I said, two days ago, my guy damn near found out who Costello's rat is.
- 不过最后在街上跟丢了 - 真的？
- But he lost him in the streets. - Really?
- 他看到那人的相貌了没？ - 没有
- Well, did he get a look at the guy? - No.
什么都没有？ 任何信息可能都对我们有帮助
I mean, nothing? Like, I mean, anything that could help us.
没有
No.
有什么建议给我吗？
So you got any advice for me? Just, I mean, generally.
没有特别调查组内鬼的信息
Costello can't do much business without coordinating with his source...
卡斯特罗没法做太多的生意
...who is here in SIU.
跟踪卡斯特罗就会找到他的线人的
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
你要去查我的人...
You're gonna be looking at my people...
查他们的银行账户，电话记录和医疗记录
...going through their bank statements, their phone calls and medical records.
他们不会请你去喝酒或去家里作客
Don't be surprised if they don't buy you a beer or invite you into their homes.
要来杯咖啡吗
Let me get you a coffee.
如果我没有当州警...
If I wasrt with the Massachusetts State Police...
而是选择去法学院学习的话...
...if I did it full-time, law school...
我一年就可以完成学业
...I'd be through it in a year.
如果我不在警队
If I wasrt a trooper.
在另一个城市也许情况会好很多
But another city. I was thinking that.
另一个城市
Another city.
另一个城市?
Another city, huh?
那就可以重新开始了
Yeah, well, that would be a clean slate.
我希望你知道，你没有必要留下来
I want you to know, you don't got to stay.
如果我们最后没有走到一起...
If we're not gonna make it...
你一定要先离开我，因为我做不到
...it's gotta be you that gets out, because I'm not capable.
我他妈的是爱尔兰人 我只会一辈子生活在错误的阴影中
I'm fucking Irish. I'll deal with something being wrong for the rest of my life.
也许我们真应该到另一个城市去
It might not be a bad idea, you know, another city.
- 我当然知道怎么识别警察 - 怎么识别？
- Of course I know how to spot a cop. - How's that?
他对我们视而不见，他就是警察
If he's not paying attention to us, he's a cop.
看到那边那个人了吗？
Lookit. You see that guy over there? Right over there.
嗯
Yeah.
他根本没在意我们，他是警察
Not paying attention to us. He's a cop.
- 对 - 你明白了吧
- Okay. - You get it now, do you?
查无此人
- 这个呢？ - 警察
- What about this guy? - Cop.
你好，这是什么狗？
Hey, how you doing? What kind of dog is that?
她没理我们，她也一定是警察
She ignored us so she must be a cop.
她是她妈的警察局长
She's probably the fucking police commissioner.
你可以走了，今晚我们用新人
You can get out of here. I'm using a new crew tonight. New guys.
- 我以为这票有我呢 - 我改主意了，今晚你休息
- I thought I was on for this. - I changed my mind. Take the night off.
Francis, we're ready for the sushi bar.
- 吉米,拿个拖把来 - 从后门走
- Jimmy, bring a mop. - Out the back.
有人总能很好的回答问题...
There's guys who answer the questions right...
还有些人不能
...and there's guys that don't. - And a pail.
你是警察
You're a cop.
什么？
What?
你无视我们，所以你是警察
You ignored us, you're a cop.
我们在猜谁是警察 你知道好看的女人一般都是警察
We're guessing who cops are. You know, most good-Iooking women are cops.
我要回家，你们和新人玩吧
Well, I'm going home, all right? He's playing with his new guys.
- 回见 - 回见
- See you later, all right? - See you later.
威廉・科斯提根
查无此人
他这次要带新人去行动
He's moving something with all new guys. A whole new crew.
我不能告诉你时间地点 这些有可能是假情报
No, no, I can't tell you what or where. It's probably disinformation.
你继续跟踪他就是了 我今天要见你
Just keep following him, all right? Listen, I need to see you today.
- 明天 - 不，今天
- Tomorrow. - No, no, no. Today.
- 你没听人提起毒品？ - 没有
- You heard nothing about drugs? - No.
也没听说新人，格拉斯特什么的？
Nothing about new guys? Nothing about Gloucester?
什么都没有,如果有什么消息的话 我肯定会知道的
Not a thing. And I would have. That information would have come to me.
不是比尔
It ain't Bill.
他没说出去
No way, he says.
跟踪卡斯特罗就会找到他的内鬼
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
我是苏利文警官
Yeah, this is Sergeant Sullivan.
我要对昆南队长进行连续监视 现在就开始
I want constant surveillance on Captain Queenan, starting right now.
好，谢谢
Good. Thank you.
警官，能不能问你个问题？ 我们他妈的为什么要跟着昆南队长？
Can I ask a question, sarge? Why the fuck are we following Captain Queenan?
看看好天主徒是怎么生活的？
To find out about the good Catholic life?
我必须追查每条线索 不管有多不可思议
I have to follow every lead, however unlikely...
不管你脆弱的感性有多么难以接受...
...however fucking painful it might be to your delicate fucking sensibilities.
谁说我脆弱？
Who told you I had delicate sensibilities?
- 我只是不喜欢这样,这样不对 - 我有理由相信
- I just don't like it, sarge. Don't feel right. - I have reason to believe...
昆南队长就是卡斯特罗的内鬼
...that Captain Queenan is Costello's rat.
跟踪他，注意不要被他发现
So just follow him and don't get made.
警官，目标出来了
Sarge, we got the target coming out.
嘿，你在哪？
Hey. Where are you?
回头
Look down the car.
- 看到我了吗？ - 看到了
- You got me? - Yeah, I gotcha.
有人跟踪你吗？
Is there a reason you would have a tail?
不会
No.
- 但是我觉得… - 比利,没人跟踪我
- Because I think... - Billy, I don't have a tail.
下一站下车，南站 在那里等10分钟
Get off at the next stop, all right? South Station. You wait there 10 minutes.
南站，等10分钟
South Station. Wait 10 minutes.
沃时街344号
他进了一栋楼，沃时街344号
He just went into a building down the waterfront. 344 Wash.
听到了吗？沃时街344号
You got that? 344 Wash.
他去了顶楼
Yeah, he went up to the top floor.
顶楼空着，没人住
Building's empty. No tenants here.
有批毒品运进来了 但我不知道详情
He's got dope coming in. I don't know where. He...
他现在很神经质
He's getting spooky, captain.
- 什么意思？ - 他失去理智了
- What? - I just saw him.
我看到他满手是血
He had blood on his hands. He's lost his fucking mind.
不知道我们来这干什么
I don't know what we're doing here, boys.
他不用他的老手下了
He's not including his regular guys. But I'll tell you something.
告诉你，迟早他会知道我的身份的 他会干掉我的
Sooner or later he's gonna find out who I am and he's gonna fucking kill me.
- 我知道，他会干掉我 - 好了
- I know it. He's gonna fucking kill me! - All right!
找到他了，昆南正在和他接头
I think we got him. I think Queenars meeting with him right now.
好了，听我说
All right, all right. Listen to me.
很抱歉，我会把你弄出来
I'm really sorry for your trouble. I swear to God I am.
也许需要些时间，但我一定会把你弄出来
I'll get you out of this. I can't do it overnight but I'll get you out.
是吗?
Yeah?
上车，有行动 大动作
Hey, get the van. We're moving. Heavy work.
- 联邦调查局怎么办？ - 他们那边泄漏消息
- What about the FBI? - They're compromised.
- 他们什么？ - 他们完蛋了！
- They're what? - They're fucked.
- 喂 - 比利，你在哪？
- Yeah. - Where are you?
我们到处找你 找到内鬼了
We've been trying to reach you. We found the rat.
现在我们要赶去干掉他
Listen, we're gonna take him out. Lookit:
地址是沃时街314号，听见了吗？
The address is 314 Washington Street. You got it?
到那里见
All right, we'll see you there.
- 什么？ - 你被跟踪了
- What? - You were followed.
- 被谁？ - 卡斯特罗的手下
- By who? - By Costello's people.
- 不可能 - 有可能，他在警局里有线人...
- Impossible. - One of the cops...
快走,快走
...he's got on the inside tipped him. Come on. Come on.
快走!
Come on!
这他妈怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?
看来都是来跟昆南接头的
Fucking shit. Looks like Queenars meeting with all of them.
对，昆南就是内鬼
Yeah, he must be our guy.
我们得要救他出来 那些人可不是开玩笑的
Sarge, we gotta get him out of here. Those guys aren't fucking around.
太迟了，快回去
Ah, Christ, it's too late. Let's go back up.
- 妈的! - 你快走!
- Shit! - You got to get out of here!
- 走消防梯 - 你怎么办？
- Take the fire escape. - What about you?
我没事的,要是你被抓到了 我就保护不了你了，快走!
I'll be fine. But if you get made I can't protect you. Now, go!
- 能借个火吗？ - 人呢?
- One of you mugs got a light? - Where's your boy?
- 在圣母大学读法律 - 你的卧底在哪？
- He's studying law at Notre Dame. - Where's your fucking boy?
- 嘿,嘿! - 妈的!
- Hey! Hey! - Goddamn motherfucker!
- 我杀了你! - 他妈的，你的卧底在哪？
- Fucking kill you! - Where's your fucking boy?
那他妈是什么东西? 你看到了吗?
What the fuck was that? Did you fucking see that?
警官，有东西从楼顶掉下来
Sarge, something just came off the building.
妈的
What the fuck?
Fuck.
什么叫从楼顶掉下来？
What do you mean, off the building?
- 有东西从楼顶掉下来 - 是尸体，那是尸体
- Something came off the fucking roof. - It's a fucking body.
我们的视线被阻 你想叫我们下车去确定一下吗？
We can't get a visual. Want us to get out?
我们的下车才看得见
We gotta get on foot if you want me to get up on this thing.
- 你他妈去哪了？ - 出什么事了？
- Where were you? - What happened?
你他妈迟到了，快上车!
You're fucking late! Get in the van!
你说有东西坠楼是什么意思？
What do you mean, off the roof?
这他妈怎么回事？我赶来找你们
What's going on? I came to meet you.
- 妈的... - 快上车!
- What the fuck...? - Get in the van!
警官，有4名带枪男子出来 要不要我们行动？
I got four armed men right out front. You want us to pursue?
不要行动，呆在车里
No, do not pursue. Stay in the car.
- 靠! 不准行动！ - 我需要知道
- Fuck. No fucking pursuit. - I need information.
什么东西从楼顶掉下来?
What came off the roof?
- 不追 - 真的他妈的扯淡
- No pursuit. - That's bullshit.
去他的
Fuck this.
快进车里来!
Fitzy! Get in the van!
上车!走，快走!
Get in the fucking van! Let's go! Move!
我抓到他了
All right. I got him.
32X向总部报告 我们被开枪射击！
32X to CP. We're being fired upon!
警员中枪，需要急救
An officer is down. I repeat, an officer is down. A trooper's been shot!
快派支援...
Send some back...
你知道为什么昆南要去那栋楼？
So do you know why Queenan went into that building?
- 不知道 - 我有更好的问题问你
- No. - Well, a better question...
为什么你的人跟踪他？
...is why the fuck were your guys following him?
我让内部调查组的人跟踪昆南的
I told Internal Investigations to follow Captain Queenan.
- 为什么？ - 那是内部调查组的事
- Why? - That's Internal Investigations' business.
狗娘养的!
Fucking piece of shit!
- 算了 - 嘿!
- All right. - Hey, hey!
- 你这个混蛋! - 放开他!
- Fucking bitch! - Let him go!
混蛋!我不用向任何人解释!
Cocksucker! I don't have to fucking explain anything to anybody!
我可以调查任何人，想查谁就查谁
I can fucking investigate anybody I want to!
- 来啊! - 我才在乎你怎么想!
- Come on! - I don't give a fuck what you think!
我有理由相信 昆南是被他自己的卧底杀害的
I got reason to believe that Queenan got killed by his fucking undercover.
撒谎
That's a fucking lie.
他的电脑里保存着很多加密档案 昆南队长的也是
He has fucking information in a locked file, as did Captain Queenan.
我要那些档案
I need access to those files.
我忘记密码了 有种你和我去车库，在那我就告诉你
I forgot the password but if you come with me I'll give it to you.
- 撒谎 - 你再说一次!
- That's a fucking lie. - Nobody calls me a liar!
闭嘴!让技术人员把那些档案解密
Shut up! Work with the tech guys to unlock those files.
- 你暂时离职 - 你说让我什么？
- Dignam, take a leave of absence. - Take a leave of what?
昆南死了，现在我是你的头
Queenan is dead. I'm your boss now.
我不管，我宁愿辞职
I don't care. I'd rather hand in my papers first.
外面多得是酒吧服务生 给你两周带薪假
World needs plenty of bartenders. Two weeks with pay.
好极了
Good.
- 你这混蛋 - 去死
- Piece of shit. - Fuck off.
- 我需要密码 - 不
- I need those codes. - No.
你想要密码
You want those codes.
你他妈跑哪去了？
So where the fuck were you?
老板让我回家
Well, boss told me to go home.
算了，他可能这么说了 不过你根本不在家
Whatever. Maybe he did, maybe he didn't. But you werert at fucking home.
你去哪了？
So where the fuck were you?
我在一家食品店，那里没信号
I was at the grocery store with no signal, all right?
有信号的时候，我才接到电话
When I got the signal, I got the call.
你想怎么样？我不是去了吗?
What the fuck do you want from me? Was I there or was I not there?
比利，比利
Billy. Billy.
怎么了?
Yeah?
恩?
知道我今天想什么吗？
You know what I thought today?
什么?
What's that?
今天没出现的人,就是内鬼
Who didn't show up today is the rat.
是吗？
Yeah?
- 所以呢? - 你从来没有迟到过
- So? - And you never been late in your life.
我打给你的时候...
When I called you...
我犯了个错误
...I made a mistake.
我给你的地址是错的
I gave you the wrong address...
但你却在正确的地址出现了
...but you showed up at the right one...
是不是？
...didn't you?
告诉我为什么这事我谁都没告诉?
Tell me why I didn't tell nobody, huh?
告诉我为什么
Tell me why.
那警察是条硬汉 我们对他做的有点过分了
That cop was tough. We were excessive with the cop.
他死了
He's dead.
我回家去了
I'm going home.
- 你的人不该那么做 - 我们俩总要死一个
- Your guys should not have done that. - One of us had to die.
所以自然是他先死了
With me it tends to be the other guy.
现在昆南死了，我无从下手
But Queenan. Now I got no access.
你杀了那个知道所有信息的人 现在迪克曼也走了，别再提他了
You killed the guy who had the info. Dignam's gone. Forget about him.
- 他辞职了 - 我他妈才不在乎迪克曼
- He resigned. - I don't give a fuck about Dignam.
他交了辞呈，弗兰克
He put in his papers, Frank.
- 他走了，我不知道他去哪了 - 迪克曼好对付，科林
- He left. I don't know where he is. - Don't get your balls in an uproar, Collie.
那家伙一心想抓住我
That Irish pissant...
稍微放出点消息，他就会找上门来
...he's so hot for me, we give him a whiff of my ass, he'll crawl right in it.
把他引出来吧
Let's give him a whiff.
- 我会的 - 别担心，我会处理的
- I will. - Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
你让我兴奋起来了
You're giving me a hard-on.
你确定是因为我吗？
Are you sure it's me?
还是因为你刚才的电话？
Not all that talk about whiffing and crawling up asses?
你他妈的说话小心点
Watch your fucking mouth.
不，是你小心点
No. You watch it.
我来帮你爽一下
Let me straighten you out.
我给你打过几次电话
I tried to call you a few times.
我知道
I know.
我不能当你朋友
Listen, I can't be a friend to you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
恩...
Yeah...
我知道
...I know.
喂
Yeah.
你用死人的手机打电话给我
You called this number on a dead guy's phone.
你是谁?
Who are you?
是你啊
So it is you.
谢天谢地你没事 我们很担心你
Well, thank God you're all right. We were very worried.
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
我是苏利文警官
This is Sergeant Sullivan.
我现在接管昆南的部门
I'm taking over Queenars unit.
我需要和迪克曼核实一下
Let me talk to Dignam to confirm it.
迪克曼警官在离职...
Staff Sergeant Dignam...
他现在很不稳定
...is on a leave of absence. He's very upset.
我们大家都是
We're all very upset.
你最好能过来一下
I think the best thing would be for you to come in.
我们需要你过来，你能来吗?
We need you to come in. Can you come in?
我们在...
We'll meet...
卧底发现卡斯特罗是联邦调查局线人
警方证实昨天下午在沼泽地带
Police confirm the body of the man found dead...
发现男尸是德拉亨特
...in the Fenway marshes yesterday...
波士顿警局的卧底警员
...is that of Timothy Delahunt, an undercover policeman for...
他的尸体昨天下午在沼泽地
...the city of Boston. This was the scene yesterday...
附近的公路上被发现
...when Delahunt's body was found in the marshes near the Fenway.
至于案件是谁人所为，作案动机为何
As for who did this or why...
还在调查之中
...that's something police are working on right now.
- 真是难以置信 - 你有什么不能相信的？
- I don't believe it. - What can't you believe?
我他妈花了一整夜把这混蛋弄到那去
I spent all fucking night dragging the poor bastard in there.
你说他们怎么这么快就找到了？
Tell me how they found him so fast.
就因为有人在3尺烂泥潭溜狗？
Somebody walking a fucking dog in three feet of mud?
那他妈狗是什么狗啊?
What kind of fucking size of dog is that?
肯定是只大狗
Must have been a big fucking dog, man.
我他妈花了整整一晚的时间
I spent all fucking night doing it, man.
真是丢人啊
I'm embarrassed.
我还是不信他是个警察 我不信
I still don't believe he was a cop. I don't believe it.
警察们说他是警察...
The cops are saying he's a cop...
好让我认为他是警察
...so I won't look for the cop.
你听好
Are you soft, Fitz?
我让你把尸体扔进沼泽
When I tell you to dump a body in the marsh...
那你就乖乖的把尸体扔进沼泽
...you dump him in the marsh.
而不是扔到一个每周四都会有人...
Not where some guy from John Hancock goes every Thursday...
固定去那做口交的地方！
...to get a fucking blowjob!
别笑了!
Don't laugh!
这他妈不是电视真人秀！
This ain't reality TV!
出发吧
Proceed.
- 怎么了? - 喂
- What? - Yeah.
有人跟踪你 两部车，跟着你并没有刻意躲避
You got a tail. Two cars. Not very subtle.
从现在开始，他们不会再遮遮掩掩地了
They're not gonna be subtle from now on. That's what I've been trying to say.
那就把他们甩掉
So get rid of them.
你没必要亲自去，弗兰克
There's no need for you to go yourself, Frank.
把他们给我甩掉!
Get rid of the fucking tail!
好吧
All right.
可恶的内鬼 我发誓要对付他们
Fucking rats. It's wearing me thin.
弗朗西斯，这个国家就是这样
Francis, it's a nation of fucking rats.
停下，停下 叫他们停下来，不用再监视了
Stop, stop. Pull them off Costello. There's no need to surveil him.
- 你说什么呢？ - 我听卧底说卡斯特罗
- What are you saying? - I got it from an undercover.
已经知道自己被跟踪了 那我们就交给卧底好了
He knows he's being followed. So let the UC take him in.
- 什么卧底？ - 昆南的那个卧底
- Undercover? - Queenars guy.
他得知昆南的死讯后给我打了电话 他现在和我联系
He called when he found out Queenan died. I'm running him.
- 和你？你得把他交给我 - 我可以告诉你卡斯特罗要去哪
- You give him to me. - No, I can give you Costello's destination.
- 你知道他要去哪？ - 是的，我还知道他要做什么
- You know where he's going? - Yes. And what he's doing.
停止跟踪，叫大家随时待命
Get rid of the tail, get Special Ops on standby.
- 我们今晚就跟这个混蛋做个了结 - 我们行动吧
- We'll take this prick tonight. - Let's go. Now.
所有人员撤回，所有人员撤回
All units fall back. All units fall back.
设菲尔德
好了，在他设菲尔德的私人仓库里
It's the warehouse he owns over on Sheffield.
那一定有集装箱或是卡车什么的 走,走
He's gotta have a container or a truck or something there. Go.
装车
Load it.
弗兰克，你怎么知道没人跟踪我们？
Frank, how do you know you don't have a tail, huh?
你他妈刚才在车里没听到吗？
Were you not in the fucking car?
万一他们换了别的车跟踪我们呢？
Yeah, what if they took one off and they put another one on?
装车
Load.
快来!
Go, go!
你等什么呢？
Come on, what are you waiting for?
弗兰克让我去查一下后面，你先走
Frank wants me to check the back. You go ahead.
- 看着你身后 - 我们走!
- Watch your fucking back. - Move out! Go on!
妈的
Cocksuckers.
混蛋!
Motherfucking shit!
操....
Motherfucking...!
快增援!
Back the fuck up!
我他妈的中弹了
They fucking shot me.
蹲低!
Get down!
来啊,混蛋!
Come on, fucking bastards!
妈的
Fuck it.
怎么回事?
How the fuck did this happen?
你是联邦调查局线人?
You're an FBI informant?
你他妈耍我吗？
Are you fucking kidding me?
成熟点吧
Grow up.
我当然要跟联邦调查局有联系
Of course I talk to the FBI.
他们知道我的身份吗？
Do they know who I am?
我从未出卖过任何人 除非那人本来就要被抓了
I never gave up anybody who wasrt going down anyway.
谁都不知道
Nobody knows nothing.
弗兰克
Frank.
弗兰克,弗兰克
Frank. Frank.
他们知道了我的事吗？
Do they know about me?
只有我知道你的事，科林
I know about you, Collie.
你知道我永远不会出卖你的
You know I'd never give you up.
- 你就像... - 像你儿子？
- You're like a... - What? Like a son?
就是这么回事吗？
To you? Is that what this is about?
杀人，胡搞了一辈子 最后连个儿子都没有
All that murdering and fucking, and no sons.
该死的，混蛋!
Fucking rat prick!
弗兰克?
Frank?
说话?
Yeah?
你是谁？
Who's this?
格温?
Gwen?
弗兰克在哪儿？
Where the hell's Frank?
弗兰克中枪了
Frank got shot.
格温，弗兰克死了
Gwen, we lost Frank.
我打死他了!
I got him!
卡斯特罗在这儿!
I got Costello here!
恭喜，干的好
Hey, good job, sarge.
不，只是...
No, it's...
给你的
For you.
- 谢谢 - 不，谢谢你！
- Thank you. - No. Thank you.
他在那等你很久了
He's been waiting here a long time for you.
你怎么找到他的？
How'd you get him without the files?
用昆南的手机联系上他的
Caller ID on Queenars phone.
你认识他吗？
You know that guy?
是，我们在警校是同学
Yeah. We were classmates in the academy together.
很高兴见到你，警官
Good to see you, trooper.
- 你好 - 我是科林 苏利文,我们在电话里聊过
- Yeah. - Colin Sullivan. We spoke on the phone.
- 没错 - 那么
- Yeah. - So.
你做卧底多久了？
Now, how long were you undercover?
很久，很久了
Long time.
- 真得很久了 - 当然
- Long fucking time. - Yeah. Yeah.
我无法表达我们有多感谢你...
Well, I can't even tell you the debt...
我会推荐你荣誉奖章的
I just want you to know I'll be recommending you for the Medal of Merit.
- 哦，是吗？ - 是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
听上去很诱人啊
That's kind of like a gold star around here, huh?
这是我们的最高荣誉
It's the highest honor we got.
我只想要恢复我的身份
Look, I just want my identity back, all right?
- 好吗 - 可以
- That's all. - All right.
- 我知道，你想重新做个警察 - 不
- I understand. You wanna be a cop again. - No, no.
不，当警察并不是我的身份 我要我自己的身份
Being a cop's not an identity. I want my identity back.
查一下你的电脑 把我之前的罪行都删除
Check your computer. Go on. You'll have to excuse my behavior.
我过去六个月来唯一打过交道的 只有一个心理医生
My only contact in the last six months has been a police shrink.
怎么样?
How's that working for you?
辅导有效果吗？
Is it helpful?
你想怎么处理 卡斯特罗安插在这里的内鬼呢？
What are you gonna do about Costello's rat in this building?
- 我会找到他的 - 是吗
- I'm gonna find the prick. - Yeah.
我会找到他，并且逮捕他的
I'm gonna find him, I'm gonna arrest him.
- 好 - 你要尽力帮我
- Good. - Anything you can do to help me...
弗兰克近期有没有提到什么人 或者联系什么人？
You know, I mean, did Frank ever mention a name...? You know, anything.
把你知道的都告诉我
Someone he was in contact with. Anything you can give me.
我做警察已经当够了
I'm all done being a cop, all right?
把钱给我，我想回家
I just want my money and I wanna go home.
好的，这样对大家都好
All right. That'll be the best thing for everybody.
非常合理
Fair enough.
只是我打不开你的档案 除非告诉我你的密码
I just, I can't get into your file unless I have your password.
密码就是我的名字
It's my name.
小威廉・科斯提根
William Costigan Jr.
他告诉我就是怕有朝一日 我需要向你这样的人解释我的身份
They gave it to me in case I had to explain myself to someone like you.
你的名字
It's your name.
好的
All right.
那倒也很合理
Fucking unreal, that... Well, makes a lot of sense.
比尔，我到隔壁去处理这个
Listen, Bill, I gotta run this in the other room.
这台电脑对我很不友好
This computer's getting all frigging blooey on me.
等我2分钟，我马上就帮你解决好
Give me two minutes. I'll have you out of here in no time.
好的，都办好了 现在把薪水给你
All right, everything checks out, so let's get you paid.
删除
人事数据库，你确定删除？
记录删除
我知道，我知道
I know.
我不是为那事来的
I know. I'm not... I'm not here for that, okay?
我不是
I'm not.
我得交给你点东西
Listen. I've gotta give you something.
你要替我保存好
Something I need you to keep.
为我
For me.
好吗?
Okay?
- 什么东西？ - 你帮我保管，只有你
- What is it? - This is for you to hold. Only you.
如果我有什么不测 或是我让你打开你才能打开
You open this if something happens to me or if I call you and I tell you to open it.
你是我唯一可以相信的人
You're the only person I can trust, all right?
求你了
Please.
- 好的 - 抱歉...
- All right. - Look, I'm sorry to even...
抱歉，我以这种方式现身
I'm sorry to even show up here like this, you know?
只是我不知道还能把这个交给谁
L... There's just no one else I could give it to.
只有你
There's no one else.
- 抱歉 - 我...
- I'm really sorry. - I...
我有...
You know, I have...
- 我... - 不管你想说什么...
- I... - Whatever you have to say...
请三思，好吗?
...think about it real hard, all right?
如果你还想说 两周之后再告诉我，好吗?
If you still wanna tell me, you tell me in two weeks, okay?
科斯提根
我刚才梦到我死了
I was dreaming I was dead.
死亡是很痛苦的 活着更容易些
Death is hard. Life is much easier.
- 这是什么？ - 打开看看
- What's this? - Open it.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Really? - Yeah.
真的?
Really?
真的
Yeah.
他们说那个小点是
And they say that this little speck...
小鸡鸡
...is a penis.
哇，是个男孩
It's a boy.
有其父必有其子
Yeah, well, one usually follows the other.
那你还能...?
Can you still...?
威廉・科斯提根 科南特大街13号
科林・苏利文 皮克林大街20号
科斯提根 电话617-555-9180 播放
我希望不用再提醒你
I hope I won't have to remind you...
如果你不找出安插在我这的内鬼
...that if you don't find this cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
最先倒霉的可不是我
...you can assume it won't be me who pays for it.
何必一再提醒我这点？
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
难道这对我现在的工作有任何帮助吗？
Would l...? Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
弗兰克，你得相信我
Frank, you gotta trust me. I can get the rat.
好吗？相信我，弗兰克
You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
你得让我放手去干
Just let me do it. Let me do what I do.
要是需要撒谎的话 你知道我他妈很在行的
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
怎么了?
What?
- 我这里混进了个警察 - 我知道
- We got a cop in my crew. - Yeah, I know.
- 我也感觉到了 - 是你们的人
- I'm kind of getting that feeling too. - He's one of yours. Inside.
- 发现什么了吗？ - 弗兰克
- You seen anything? - Frank.
弗兰克，我没有权限查看卧底档案 昆南和...
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
知道吗?我还以为我才是骗子
- I'm doing my... - You know what, I thought I was the liar.
嘿，我可以解释的！
Hey, I can explain that!
卡斯特罗把所有的东西都录了下来
Costello recorded everything.
为了保险起见 他把所有的带子都放进一个小盒 交给他的律师保管
He put all the tapes in a box and kept them with his lawyer. That was his insurance.
律师找了我
His lawyer came to me.
想像下，你这死内鬼
Imagine that, you rat fuck.
卡斯特罗最信任的是我
Costello trusted me more than anyone.
录音的音质足够好? 开始我还有点担心
Sound quality good enough? Because I was a little worried.
- 你想要什么？ - 我告诉过你我要自己的身份
- What do you want? - I told you I want my identity back...
你这两面派
...you two-faced faggot.
- 你在哪? - 三点钟，昆南死的地方
- All right, where are you? - Three o'clock. Where Queenan died.
开着手机
You keep your cell on.
开门
Open the door.
开...我们不是已经谈过了吗？
Open... Didrt we already talk about this?
这是我的工作
This is my job.
- 别动！举起手！ - 嘿!
- Freeze! Get your fucking hands up! - Hey!
嘿，把枪放下！
Put the fucking gun down!
把枪放下！我来是...
Put the gun down, all right? I came here to talk some sense into you.
- 手! - 好的，专业点
- Hands! - Just act professional.
- 我给你钱 - 你说什么？
- I can get you your money. - What did you say?
- 我可以给你钱 - 你来这儿不是和来谈判的
- I can get you your money. - You didn't come here to talk, all right?
- 你是来被捕的 - 你有盘狗屁录音又怎么样？
- You came here to get arrested. - You got fucking tapes? Of what?
卡斯特罗是我的线人 我是卧底?去你妈的，你能证明吗？
Costello was my informant. I was a rat? Fuck you! Prove it.
他为我工作，他是我的线人
He was working for me. He was my informant.
闭嘴，起来
Shut your fucking mouth. Come on, get up!
这算什么? 你逮捕警察吗？ 开枪啊?
What is this, a citizers arrest? Blow me, all right?
我们两个只有一个是警察，比尔 你知道吗，比尔？
Only one of us is a cop here, Bill. You understand that, Bill?
- 没人知道... - 闭上你的臭嘴!
- No one knows you. - Shut the fuck up!
我是麻萨诸塞州警官 你他妈算什么？
I'm a sergeant in the Massachusetts State Police. Who the fuck are you?
- 我把你的档案都删了！ - 你把我的档案删了？
- I erased you! - You erased me, huh?
继续呀！干掉警察啊！ 看看会怎么样
Yeah, go ahead, shoot a cop, Einstein. Watch what happens.
怎么样？我会打爆你的头!
This bullet would go right through your fucking head!
- 再然后呢？ - 葬礼游行，洗礼什么的？
- Watch what happens! - What, so you can get the parade, huh?
你这混蛋，我他妈要逮捕你!
The bagpipes and bullshit? Fuck you! Fuck you, I'm fucking arresting you!
- 你要那么做就太他妈蠢了 - 闭嘴!
- That's the stupidest thing you could do. - Shut the fuck up!
我他妈不管什么罪名
I could give a fuck if the charges don't stick.
我就他妈就要逮捕你
I'm still fucking arresting you.
起来
Get up.
放下武器！ 放开苏利文警官！
Drop your weapon and step away from Sergeant Sullivan.
是我打电话给你的 只打给你了
I called you. You specifically. Look:
我知道我的，我不会开枪 我告诉过你在楼下见我
You know who I am. I'm not gonna shoot. I told you to meet me downstairs.
放下武器！ 放开苏利文警官!
Put your weapon on the deck and step away from Sergeant Sullivan!
迪克曼在哪？ 我告诉过你带迪克曼来！
Where's Dignam? I told you to bring Dignam!
开枪！打他！
Shoot this motherfucker! Would you fucking shoot!
- 把枪放在地上！之后我们再谈 - 听着，苏利文是内鬼！
- Drop your weapon. We'll discuss it. - Look, he's Costello's rat, all right?
我有录音，文件 所有的证据都能证明！
I got boxes of tapes! Evidence! Other documents proving it!
也许你有
Maybe you do.
但现在你要放下武器
But right now I need you to drop the weapon!
我告诉过你，我有证据证明 他就是卡斯特罗的内鬼
I have evidence cold-linking this prick to Costello, all right?
- 干掉这个疯子！ - 你知道我是谁
- Would you shoot this fucking prick! - You know who I am.
- 你知道我是谁 - 开枪射他
- You know who I am. - Shoot this fucking prick.
现在我要把他带到楼下去
I'm taking him downstairs now.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我真是迫不及待得想看 你怎么和陪审团解释这一切
I can't wait to see you explain this to a Suffolk County jury...
你这傻x
...you fucking cocksucker.
这他妈好一定会很好玩
This is gonna be fucking fun.
杀了我吧
Just fucking kill me.
快点杀了我吧
我会的
I am killing you.
你觉得你是唯一一个内鬼？
Did you think you were the only one he had on the inside?
卡斯特罗打算把我们出卖给联邦调查局的
Costello was gonna sell us to the FBI.
我们现在在一条船上，你明白吗？
It's you and me now, you understand?
我们要互相照顾，你明白吗？
We gotta take care of each other, you understand?
给我
Give me that.
Right. Slow. March.
我在试图制服北芮根时...
I attempted to subdue Trooper Barrigan...
他向我开了枪 我奋力开了一枪
...at which time he drew down on me, and I was able to squeeze off one shot...
开枪击中他的头部
...and strike him in the head.
之后我立即检查科斯提根...
At that time I immediately checked the vitals...
和布朗两名州警的呼吸心跳
...on both Troopers Brown and Costigan...
发现他们已经死亡了
...and discovered that they had expired.
请把这个也记录下来
I just wanna go on record.
我推荐威廉 科斯提根 作为荣誉勋章候选人
I'm recommending William Costigan for the Medal of Merit.
- 愿他得到永远的安息 - 准备好了吗?
- Eternal rest grant unto him, O Lord. - Ready?
- 愿永恒之光照耀其身 - 折
- And let perpetual light shine upon him. - Fold.
让他安息吧,阿门
May he rest in peace. Amen.
愿忠实逝者的灵魂伴随主的慈悲...
May his soul and the souls...
安息
...of all the faithful departed, through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
阿门
Amen.
准备，执礼
Detail. Half left. Face.
准备鸣枪
Prepare to fire.
鸣枪！
Fire.
准备鸣枪，鸣枪！
Prepare to fire. Fire.
礼毕
Detail. Half right. Face.
我一会来找你们
I'll catch up with you guys.
孩子怎么样了？
What about the baby?
狗狗
Hi, pup.
开枪吧
Okay.
谢谢观赏！